<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०२ samAShrayaNa-paramparA on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०२ samAShrayaNa-paramparA on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>०१ EmpAr (Govinda Bhattar)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/01_EmpAr_Govinda_Bhattar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/01_EmpAr_Govinda_Bhattar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the village of Madhuramangalam, EmpAr was born to Kamalanayana Bhattar and Periya PirATTi, the younger daughter of Periya Tirumalainambi in the year Krodana, thai month when Punarvasu star was in ascendance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(His vaibhavam is linked closely to the vaibhavam of EmperumAnAr and so no separate description of them is included here).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Final days&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the time of EmperumAnAr, Govinda Bhattar was teaching the esoteric works of Udaiyavar to ParASara Bhattar and others as per the wish of EmperumAnAr. All the time he was living in the memory of EmperumAnAr. One day he meditated on the holy feet of Udaiyavar. As he was not being able to live without Udaiyavar, he prayed to Periya Perumal and wished to attain Paramapadam. He called his pradAna Sishya, ParASara Bhattar and told him, &amp;ldquo;Oh Bhattar! Do not think that you are the son of AzhvAn, have learnt well all the SAstrAs, you are the adopted son of Namperumal and proud of yourself. Understand and remember that the holy feet of Udaiyavar show the right path. You teach the Ramanuja darSana granthams to all the disciples&amp;rdquo;. Then, he prayed to the holy feet of Udaiyavar and attained Paramapadam. His last rites were conducted through ciRia Govinda Perumal by ParASara Bhattar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०२ Bhattar (ParASara Bhattar)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/02_Bhattar_ParASara_Bhattar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/02_Bhattar_ParASara_Bhattar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;KoorattAzhvAn was the pradhAna Sishya of EmperumAnAr. AzhvAn mastered all the SAstrAs. He had deep devotion to EmperumAnAr. He had all the attributes (guNams) that are expected of a disciple. People used to say that there was no one like AzhvAn. He will not do any harm to anyone. He cannot bear the sufferings of others. He would not even walk over the grass for the fear of stamping on the grass and disfiguring it. He is very compassionate and mild mannered person who shuns cruelty in any form (AnruSamsaya pradhAnar). AzhvAn used to take uncavrtti (bhikshA) from the households of Brahmins. He used to cook food with the grains received as bhikshA, offered the same as nivedanam to the Lord and used to take the same as prasAdam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०३ NamjIyar (நஞ்சீயர்)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/03_NamjIyar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/03_NamjIyar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the time of ParASara Bhattar, NamjIyar, the sampradAya Pravartakar was staying in Srirangam. He composed a grantham, onpatinAyiRappaDi (9,000 paDi), a commentary for TiruvAimozhi that he learnt from Bhattar. This work was styled in line with SrI BhAshyam. He asked his SishyAs. &amp;ldquo;Is there anyone who can write these notes in a palm leaf?&amp;rdquo; The disciples replied, &amp;ldquo;One person by name NambUr Varadarajar from the south bank visits here often. He can write very well&amp;rdquo;. NamjIyar asked them to bring that person. When Varadarajar came to meet NamjIyar, he asked him to write a grantham in a palm leaf. He saw what he has written and noticed that the handwriting was good and very tidy. However, the jIyar said, &amp;ldquo;This is a work on TiruvAimozhi and so this can be written only with the help of a capable person blessed with an AcAryan. This person is yet to be blessed with panca samskAram. How we can take his service to do this?&amp;rdquo; On hearing about this, Varadarajar prostrated at the feet of NamjIyar and appealed to him, &amp;ldquo;Devareer! Please reform me and accept me as a disciple who can fulfil your wises&amp;rdquo;. NamjIyar was impressed and initiated panca samskAra rituals to him. The jIyar did upadeSam of his work on onpatinAyiRappaDi vyAkhyAnam as well TiruvAimozhi to Varadarajar. The jIyar asked him to write this with out any mistakes and handed over the notes to him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०४ Nampillai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/04_Nampillai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/04_Nampillai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nampillai was born in the agrahAram of Nambur in the month of Kaartigai when KrutikA nakshtram was in ascendance. He completed kAlakshepam under NamjIyar and was the proponent of the sampradAyam after the time of NamjIyar. He was teaching traditional granthams in Srirangam. PeriyavAcchAn Pillai, VaDakku Tiruveedhi Pillai, PinpAzhagiya Perumal jIyar, EyuNNi Madhava Perumal and several other scholars of eminence were undergoing kAlakshepam under Nampillai.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Question of the King&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nampillai was an acknowledged expert in rendering Bhagavad VishAya kAlakshepam. One day a group of SishyAs were coming out after the conclusion Bhagavad Vishaya kAlakshepam by Nampillai. It was told by many that on seeing the group of the disciples, a king asked, &amp;ldquo;Is this group of people from the sannidhi of Namperumal or the group of SishyAs of Nampillai?&amp;rdquo; Thus, Nampiilai had a huge group of SrI VaishNavAs as his disciples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०५ VaDakku tiruvIdhi Pillai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/05_VaDakku_tiruvIdhi_Pillai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/05_VaDakku_tiruvIdhi_Pillai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MuDumbai Nambi belonging to the SrIvatsa Kulam was one of the seventy four simhAsanAdhipatis. He took shelter under the holy feet of EmperumAnAr. His son was Ramanuja Nambi and his son was MuDumbaiyANDAn whose son was Devapperumal and his son was iLaiyAzhvAn. ILaiyAzhvAn had two sons, VaDakku tiruveedhi Pillai and MannAr. VaDakku tiruveedhi Pillai was born in the year Sarvajit, Ani month when the SvAti nakshatram was in ascendance. His another name was KrishnapAdar. There was one another person by the name NaDuvil tiruveedhi Pillai. Since KrishnapAdar lived in the vaDakku veedhi (North street), he was called VaDakku tiruveedhi Pillai. He took refuge under the holy feet of Nampillai and underwent TiruvAimozhi kAlakshepam under him. He has written on palm leaves, the muppattARAyirappaDi (36,000) known as EDu vyAkhyAnam of Nampillai. His sons were Pillai LokachAriyar and AzhagiyamaNavALap- perumal nAyanAr.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०६ KeSavAchAryar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/06_KeSavAchAryar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/06_KeSavAchAryar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;KeSavAchAryar is the son of SrI RangAchAriyar (RangageSvarar). He was born at Tirunarayanapurm in the year Kara, mAsi month, Punarvasu Nakshatram.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;taniyan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;श्रीरङ्गार्यगुरोः सूनुं धीशमादिगुणार्णवम् ।&#xA;केशवार्यगुरुंA वन्दे द्रामिडाम्नायदेशिकम् ॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SrIrangAryaguroH sUnum dhISamAdiguNArNavam | keSavAryagurum vande drAmiDAmnAyadeSikam ||&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०७ KamalAvAsar (SrinivAsAchAryar)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/07_KamalAvAsar_SrinivAsAchAryar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/07_KamalAvAsar_SrinivAsAchAryar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;KamalAvAsar (SrinivAsAchAryar) is the son of KeSavAchAryar. He was born at Tirunarayanapurm in the year dhundubhi, Purattasi month, SravaNa Nakshatram.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;taniyan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;केशवार्यगुरोः सूनुं धीशमादिगुणार्णवम् ।&#xA;श्रीनिवासगुरुंA वन्दे द्रामिडाम्नायदेशिकम् ॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;keSavAryaguroH sUnum dhISamAdiguNArNavam | SrInivAsagurum vande drAmiDAmnAyadeSikam ||&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०८ KeSavAchAryar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/08_KeSavAchAryar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/02_samAShrayaNa-paramparA/08_KeSavAchAryar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;KeSavAchAryar is the son of SrinivAsAchAryar (KamalAvAsar). He was born at Tirunarayanapurm in the year SvabhAnu, Purattasi month, JyeshTha Nakshatram.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[187]] taniyan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;श्रीरङ्गराजदिव्याज्ञालब्धसाम्राज्यलाञ्छनम् ।&#xA;गुरुंA द्रमिडवेदानां केशवार्यमुपास्महे॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SrIrangarAja divyAj~nAlabdha sAmrAjyalAnchanam | gurum dramiDavedAnAm keSavAryamupAsmahe ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Up to this, the vaibhavams of AcAryAs of samASrayaNa paramparA of SrImad Adi vaN SaThakopa YatIndra mahAdeSikan have been covered. From now, the vaibhavams from SrImad Adi vaN SaThakopa YatIndra mahAdeSikan and SrI sannidhi guruparamparA (succeeding Azhagiyasingars) will be covered.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
