<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;SRI VAISHNAVA BRAHMANS - rangAchAri on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;SRI VAISHNAVA BRAHMANS - rangAchAri on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>14 Archaka Sri Vaishnava Brahmans</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/14_Archaka_Sri_Vaishnava_Brahm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/14_Archaka_Sri_Vaishnava_Brahm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amongst Sri Vaishnavas God is worshipped in two different ways. One way is worshipping God in one&amp;rsquo;s own house and it is called Svarthayajanam. This domestic worship of God or Svarthayajanam has already been described under Panchakāla observances of an orthodox Sri Vaishnava Brahman. The other method of worship or Parārthayajanam is meant for all people. This is the form of worship that is usually adopted in all temples. All the temple rituals connected with the daily worship, worshipping on special occasions and the establishment of idols and invoking of God&amp;rsquo;s spirit have all to be carried out by men specially trained or initiated for these purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Pratishtha Ceremony of Utsava Vigrahas in Temples</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/15_Pratishtha_Ceremony_of_Utsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/15_Pratishtha_Ceremony_of_Utsa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In every temple we find one kind of image placed inside in the garbhagrha and another just in front of it. The one in the garbhagrha is one usually made of stone or mortar and its appearance is usually black and shining. In front of these stone or mortar vigrahas are placed metallic vigrahas. The mūla vigrahas are fixed to the spot and cannot be removed from the place. The metallic vigrahas placed in front of the mūla vigrahas are usually taken out whenever necessary in procession, and hence, they are called utsava vigrahas. Both these are prepared by smiths who are called Silpis. They being to the Kammala (Tamil) or Kamsali (Telugu) caste. The preparation of these images is done according to certain principles laid down in the Silpa Śastra. These rules or principles guiding them in the matter of making these images are either handed down from generation to generation by actual workers or learned from written works of Śilpa Śastras.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Daily Worship in Temples according to the Pancharatra System</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/16_Daily_Worship_in_Temples_ac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/16_Daily_Worship_in_Temples_ac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Archakas concerned should finish their daily observances (nitya karmas) before beginning the worship of God in the temple They should wash their legs up to the knees and clean their hands up to the wrist with clean water, before entering the temple. After cleaning their legs and feet they come to the front of the temple and standing in front of the outer doorway which is closed they repeat the suprabhatam to awaken God and then salute him in the temple. The musicians, if available, play on their nagasarams. The front doors of the temple are opened after the recital of the suprabhatam as the Archakas think that God is awakened. As soon as they enter the temple precincts they show respect to God by obeisance and then, with the permission of the dvarapalakas, they enter the temple after going round the prakaram once. (See Pl. IX-B.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Brahmotsavam or Car Festival</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/17_Brahmotsavam_or_Car_Festiva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/17_Brahmotsavam_or_Car_Festiva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Brahmotsavam ceremony in a temple is usually performed during a particular month, and this varies with the locality. For example the Brahmotsavam at Conjeeveram and Lakshmipuram (near Kuppam) is celebrated on the same day. It is performed during the month of Vaikasi every year. In this month the festival days are fixed with reference to the avabhrtasnanam or Tirtavāri day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At Conjeeveram and Lakshmipuram the tīrtavari day is the &amp;ldquo;Sravanam&amp;rdquo;, i.e., the day on which this star is predominant. This day is usually the ninth day of the festival.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
