<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०३ ahobilam on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०३ ahobilam on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 SrImad AdivAN SaThakopa yatIndra MahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/01_SrImad_AdivAN_SaThakopa_yatIndra_M/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/01_SrImad_AdivAN_SaThakopa_yatIndra_M/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the period of GaTikASatAm Ammal, SrImad Adi vAN SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan was the leading light of the ViSishTAdvaita siddAntam (sampradAya pravartakar).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Kruta yugam, SanatkumArar brought the Lord, Tirunarayanan from Satyalokam and consecrated here in Bhulokam. He was doing AradhAnam of the Lord. Hence the name of the temple came to be known as &amp;ldquo;nArAyaNAdri&amp;rdquo;. In the next tretA yugam, dattAtreyA along with His four SishyAs, the Veda PurushAs were reciting all the time, the Vedas on the banks of the Veda PushkarANi. As such, this temple is called &amp;ldquo;VedAdri&amp;rdquo;. In dvApara yugam, the third yugam, Krishna and Balarama were worshipping the Lord of this temple. Hence it is known as &amp;ldquo;yAdavAdri&amp;rdquo;. In the present Kali yugam, EmperumAnar (YatirAjar) visited the temple and renovated it. He stayed in this divya deSam for several years and was doing ArAdhanam. So the temple is known as &amp;ldquo;yatiSailam&amp;rdquo;. This temple at Tirunarayanapuram is a famous one and of great divinity and a PuNya kshetram.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 SrImannArAyaNa yatIndra MahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/02_SrImannArAyaNa_yatIndra_MahAdeSika/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/02_SrImannArAyaNa_yatIndra_MahAdeSika/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From here on, we will be covering the caritrams of SrImad Azhagiyasingars of Ahobila maTham who reigned from the throne (AsthAnam) of SrI maTham after SrImad Adi VaN SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan. Lord Narasimhan has the name of Azhagiyasingar. Therefore, the AcAryas who perform daily ArAdhanam for Him are also called Azhgiyasingars from ancient times. We will address these AcAryAS as &amp;ldquo;Azhagiyasingars&amp;rdquo; from now on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We could not obtain the time and year of birth, date, and the names of the parents from their pUrvASramams of many Azhagiyasingars. We could not gather their vaibhavam from the days before they entered the sanyAsa ASramam. Hence, we had to rely on the material assembled in the Guru ParamparA source.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 SrI ParAnkuSa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/03_SrI_ParAnkuSa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/03_SrI_ParAnkuSa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar is from Kanchipuram region and from MalayAnkuLam agrahAram. He was born in the month of thai, when SravaNa Nakshatram was in ascendance. His pUrvASrama tirunAmam was Kantadai KrishnayajvA. From this name, we could infer that he has conducted yAgAs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He ascended the SrI maTham ASthAnam in Nandana year, Panguni month, (March 1473), PaurNami tithi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Yati went on sancAram from Tirunarayanapuram to Perumal Koyil (Kanchipuram). He performed MangaLASAsanam to Perumdevi tAyAr and PeraruLAlan. He stayed at Kanchipuram for a few days. The scholars of this divya deSam sought the refuge at his sacred feet and attended kAlakshepam on SrI BhAshyam and other esoteric granthams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 SrInivAsa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/04_SrInivAsa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/04_SrInivAsa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born in Marghazhi month, when ChitrA nakshatram was in ascendance. He ascended to the AsthAnam of SrI maTham in Krodhi year, thai month (January 1485).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From Srimushnam, he visited many divya deSams and arrived at the abhimAna sthalam of Singarkoyil celebrated by purANas. He stayed here for a few more days and conducted kAlakshepams on the various ubhaya VedAnta granthams to SishyAs. Then from there, this Yati went on a sancAram to visit northern divya deSams of Ahobilam, Dwaraka, Gokulam, BrundAvanam, MathurA, MayApuri, Avanti, Ayodhya etc. Then he went to Kanchipuram and returned back to Singarkoyil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 sarvatantra svantantra SrI SaThakopa yatIndra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/05_sarvatantra_svantantra_SrI_SaThako/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/05_sarvatantra_svantantra_SrI_SaThako/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;mahAdeSikan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar belongs to Atreya gotram and was born at Kandalur in the month of Kartigai, KrittikA nakshatram. He ascended the AcArya pITham in pramAdISa year, month of Chittirai (April 1493), KrishNa paksha dvItiyai tithi. Since this Azhagiyasingar had mastery over all SAstrAs, the scholars gave him the title of sarvatantra svatantrar. This Azhagiyasingar conducted kAlakshepams on SrI BhAshyam and other granthams. He performed MangaLASAsanams of EmperumAns at Perumal Koyil, Tiruppati and other divya deSams. He started on his sancAram to divya deSams in the north. During this trip, he arrived at the banks of River Krishna.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 SrI (shashTa) ParAnkuSa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/06_SrI_shashTa_ParAnkuSa_yatIndra_mah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/06_SrI_shashTa_ParAnkuSa_yatIndra_mah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born in the agrahAram named KaraLapAkkam near Thiruvallur. He belonged to BhAradvAja gotram. He was born in the month of thai, Poorattadi nakshatram. His pUrvASrama tirunAmam was VidvAn Vangeepuram Venkatacharya SvAmi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He ascended the throne of SrI Ahobila maTham on KALayukti samvatsaram, thai month, Krishna paksha dasami tithi (January 1499). [[225]] This Azhagiyasingar was the most renowned one after SrImad Adi vaN SaThakopa jIyar. He was celebrated for his j~nAnam, anushThAnam etc. He was the foremost among those with total detachment from material pleasures. At his sacred feet, many AcArya Purushas sought refuge and thrived. He blessed them with the performance of samASrayaNam, bharanyAsam and kAlakshepams in SrI BhAshyam and other sacred texts. Even today, SrI VaishNavAs belonging to DeSika sampradAyam recite his taniyan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 SrI SaThakOpa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/07_SrI_SaThakOpa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/07_SrI_SaThakOpa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born in Ilankadu, a vaidika agrahAram in Kanchi region. He belonged to BhAradvAja gotram. His tirunakshatram is VaikAsi VisAkam. He ascended the throne of SrI maTham in AngIrasa year, Masi month (February 1513) He entered in to sanyASramam at the age of twenty five at the command of Malolan. He performed ArAdhanam for the Lord. He went on sancAram from Ahobilam to Setu. His ASrama name is SrI SaTakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan. Besides the honorific title of &amp;ldquo;SrI vaN SaThakopa&amp;rdquo; for all Azhagiyasingars, this jIyar has additional titles like &amp;ldquo;SatalekinI lekhanAnuguNa, kavitAdhurandhara, kavitArkiKaNTIrava&amp;rdquo;. So, his full ASrama name is known as &amp;ldquo;SatalekinI lekhanAnuguNa, [[228]] kavitAdhurandhara, kavitArkiKaNTIrava SrI vaN SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan&amp;rdquo;. This Azhagiyasingar has written a nATakam (drama) in Sanskrit and prAkrutam, named &amp;ldquo;VaasantikA PariNayam. (This nATakam was translated in to Tamil about forty years ago in Sri Nrusimha PriyA. Its English version is at the Ahobilavalli link of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sadagopan.org&#34;&gt;www.sadagopan.org&lt;/a&gt; portal, e book 4).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 SrI ParAnkuSa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/08_SrI_ParAnkuSa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/08_SrI_ParAnkuSa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born during the Marghazhi month, aSvini Nakshatram. He entered in to sanyAsa ASramam during the Vishu samvatsaram, panguni month (April 1522), Sukla paksha ekAdaSI dinam. He stayed permanently at Srirangam during his reign and performed nitya MangaLASAsanam of the Srirangam divya dampatis. He taught SrI BhAshyam and other granthams to his disciples. He attained Paramapadam on a Hevilambi year, Marghazhi month (January 1538), Krishna paksha Pancami day at Srirangam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 SrImannArAyaNa yatIndra mahadeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/09_SrImannArAyaNa_yatIndra_mahadeSika/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/09_SrImannArAyaNa_yatIndra_mahadeSika/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born in the month of Ani, ArudrA nakshatram. He ascended to the AsthAnam in HeviLambi year, Marghazhi month (January 1538), PaurNami tithi. He started his sancAram from Srirangam to Tirukkudantai (Kumbakonam) and performed MangaLASAsanam of Lord ArAvamudan there. He stayed there for a while. At ArAvamudan sannidhi, he performed kaimkaryams like construction of ManTapam etc. From Tirukkudantai, he went on to Srimushnam, Tirukkovalur, Perumal Koyil (Kanchipuram), Tirumala etc., and performed his MangaLASAsanam to EmperumAns there before arriving at Ahobilam. There he stayed and was performing MangaLASAsanam to the nava Narasimhars. At Ahobilam, he constructed MaNTapams, steps etc., as kaimkaryams. On the Subhakrut Ani month (July 1542), Krishna paksha Caturti dinam, this jIyar ascended to SrI VaikuNTham.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 SrI SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/10_SrI_SaThakopa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/10_SrI_SaThakopa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born on VaikAsi month, Visaka nakshatram. He ascended the AcArya pITham in Subhakrt year, month of Ani, (July 1542), Krishna paksha dvitIyai tithi day at Ahobilam. From Ahobilam, SrImad Azhagiyasingar proceeded to Tirumala for the MangaLASAsanam of Tiruvengadamudaiyan. The MangaLASAsanam of the divya deSa EmperumAns of the southern parts of the country followed. After these sancArams, he arrived at Tirunarayanapuram and stayed there. VedAnta kAlakshepam for many SishyAs took place at Tirunarayanapuram. SrImad Azhagiyasingar ascended to Paramapadam in SiddhArthi year, Ani month, (July 15559), Krishna paksha dvAdaSI tithi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 SrInivAsa yatindra mahadeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/11_SrInivAsa_yatindra_mahadeSikan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/11_SrInivAsa_yatindra_mahadeSikan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born at Tiruvallur in the month of aippasi,&#xA;mUla nakshatram. He belonged to Vangeepuram BhAradwaja gotram.&#xA;He ascended to the AcArya pITham in the year SiddhArthi, month of&#xA;Ani (July 1559) at Tirunarayanapuram. From here, he went on&#xA;sancAram to Tiruppati, Tiruvallur, Perumal Koyil and other divya&#xA;deSams and reached Srirangam. At Srirangam, he spent a few years.&#xA;Here, he conducted many kAlakshepams on our darSanam for his&#xA;SishyAs. From Srirangam, SrImad Azhagiyasingar returned to&#xA;Tirunarayanapuram. There he stayed for a few days and was&#xA;conducting kAlakshepams. Now, SrIranganathan ordered SrImad&#xA;Azhagiyasingar to return to Srirangam. He returned back to Srirangam&#xA;and here he was doing MangaLASAsanam to Azhagiya Manavalan. In&#xA;the year Vilambi, month of Chittirai (April 1598), Krishna paksha&#xA;Caturti dinam, SrI SrInivasa yatIndra mahAdeSikan ascended to&#xA;Paramapadam.&#xA;His AsthAna nirvAka kAlam - 38 years, 9 months&#xA;This Azhagiyasingar is one of the Ahobila maTham AcAryAs, who&#xA;observed more years of cAturmAsyam until his nirvAka kAlam after Adi&#xA;vAN SaThakopa jIyar. He visited a few divya deSams many times and&#xA;did many kAlakshepams on darSana granthams.&#xA;taniyan&#xA;पराङ्कुशशठारातिपदाम्भोजैकधारकम्&#xA;।&#xA;श्रीनिवासमुनिं वन्दे मादृशामपि तारकम्&#xA;॥&#xA;parAnkusA SaThArAti padAmbhojaikadhArakam |&#xA;SrInivAsamunim vande mAdrSAmapi tArakam ||&#xA;Mangalamalai&#xA;तुलामूलेऽवतीर्णाय किंAगृहेशकृAपावशात्&#xA;।&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sadagopan.org&#34;&gt;www.sadagopan.org&lt;/a&gt; AcArya Vaibhavam&#xA;233&#xA;श्रीनिवासयतिन्द्राय श्रीशकैङ्कर्यशालिने॥&#xA;सिद्धार्थिमिथुने कृ ष्णद्वादश्यां श्रीहरेर्मठे।&#xA;सीताकान्तान्तरङ्गाय स्वभिषिक्ताय मङ्गलम्॥&#xA;tulAmUle avatIrNAya kimgrheSakrpAvaSAt |&#xA;SrInivAsayatindrAya SrISakainkaryaSAline ||&#xA;siddhArthimithune krishNadvAdaSyAm SrIharermaThe |&#xA;sItAkAntAntarangAya svabhishiktAya mangalam ||&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 SrImannArAyaNa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/12_SrImannArAyaNa_yatIndra_mahAdeSika/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/12_SrImannArAyaNa_yatIndra_mahAdeSika/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born at Tiruvallur in the month of Purattasi,&#xA;pUrvaphalguni (pUram) nakshatram. He belonged to Vangeepuram&#xA;BhAradwAja gotram. He ascended to the AsthAnam at Srirangam in&#xA;the year Vilambi, month of Chittirai (April 1598). From there, he went&#xA;on sancAram to Tirunarayanapuram. Here, he stayed for a long time,&#xA;doing ManagaLASAsanam of Tirunarayanan. Here at the BrundAvanam&#xA;of SrImad Adi vAN SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan, did&#xA;kAlakshepams twelve times on SrI BhAshyam. After staying here for a&#xA;long time, he went to Ahobilam, Tiruppati, Tiruvallur, Perumal Koyil&#xA;and other divya deSams. He returned again to Tirunarayanapuram. He&#xA;ascended to SrI VaikuNTham in the year AngIrasa, month of Purattasi&#xA;(September 1632), Krishna paksha shashTi tithi day.&#xA;His AsthAna nirvAka kAlam - 34 years, 5 months&#xA;taniyan&#xA;श्रीपराङ्कुशयोगीन्द्रश्रीनिवासपदाश्रयम।्&#xA;श्रीमन्नारयणमुनिं वन्दे वेदान्तदेशिकम ्॥&#xA;SrIparAnkuSayogIndra SrInivAsapadASrayam |&#xA;SrImannArayaNamunim vande vedAntadeSikam ||&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sadagopan.org&#34;&gt;www.sadagopan.org&lt;/a&gt; AcArya Vaibhavam&#xA;234&#xA;MangalamAlai&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 SrIvIrarAghava yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/13_SrIvIrarAghava_yatIndra_mahAdeSika/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/13_SrIvIrarAghava_yatIndra_mahAdeSika/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born at Thiruvallur. His tirunakshatram is Ani, Utthiradam. He belonged to Vangeepuram BhAradwaja gotram. He entered the sanyAsa ASramam at Tirunarayanapuram in the year, AngIrasa, Purattasi month (September 1632), Krishna Pancami tithi. He arrived at Tirumalirumcholai (Azhagar Koyil) after sancAram from Tirunarayanapuram to Srirangam and had MangaLASAsanams at divya deSams on the way. He stayed at Tirumalirumcholai for an extended period. From here, he proceeded to Azhwar Tirunagari. He worshipped AdippirAn and SvAmi NammAzhvAr. The honors (MaryAdais) to the jIyar at AzhvAr sannidhi were similar to the same as for Adi vaN SaThakopa jIyar with appropriate aruLappADu. Azhagiyasingar accepted all the sannidhi honors with enthusiasm and returned to his maTham. The temple kaimkaryaparars took leave of Azhagiyasingar and returned back to the temple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 SrImannArAyaNa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/14_SrImannArAyaNa_yatIndra_mahAdeSika/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/14_SrImannArAyaNa_yatIndra_mahAdeSika/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born in Pullambhuthamkudi divya deSam on Adi month, Uttarada nakshatram. He ascended to the AsthAnam of Ahobila maTham, in Nala samvatsaram, aippasi month (October 1676), Krishna paksha Pancami tithi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He stayed at Srirangam for a few days. At that time, a few SishyAs approached him and asked for the blessings of their AcAryan for creating a grantham praising on the glories of our AcArya lineage (GuruparamaparA PrabhAvam). Responding to their plea, SrImad Azhagiyasingar created a new grantham, &amp;ldquo;AcArya guNadarSam&amp;rdquo;. He did upadeSam on the content of this grantham elaborately. He advised his SishyAs to rely on this grantham for their succor (ujjIvanam) and spiritual well being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 SrI KalyANa vIrarAghava yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/15_SrI_KalyANa_vIrarAghava_yatIndra_m/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/15_SrI_KalyANa_vIrarAghava_yatIndra_m/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born in Esanoor agrahAram near Kanchipuram. He belonged to taTTai vAdhUla gotram. He was born in thai month, Chitra nakshatram. He ascended to the AsthAnam of Ahobila maTham in Akshaya year, Adi month (August 1686), PaurNami tithi dinam. He went on sancAram from Tirukkandiyoor to Srimushnam, Tiruccittirakudam, Tiruvaheendrapuram, Tirukkovalur and other divya deSams, and did his MangaLASAsanam of the EmperumAns. He stayed permanently at Perumal Koyil (Kanchipuram) and was worshipping the Lord, PeraruLALan and Perumdevi tAyAr. The VaishNavAs of Kanchi sought the lotus feet of SrImad Azhagiyasingar and participated in the kAlakshepams of SrI BhAshyam and other sampradAyic granthams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 SrISaThakopa yatIndra mahAdesikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/16_SrISaThakopa_yatIndra_mahAdesikan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/16_SrISaThakopa_yatIndra_mahAdesikan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born in Sokattur agrahAram in Kanchipuram region in Margazhi month, when MrugasIrsha nakshatram was in ascendance. He ascended the throne of Ahobila maTham during the Bhava Varsham, Purattasi month (October 1694), KrshNa paksha dasami tithi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After getting the permission of Perumal Koyil PeraruLALan, he started his sancAram for the divya deSams in the South. He performed MangaLASasanams of SrI Devanathan and SrI HayagrIvan at Tiruvaheendrapuram. At this time, a MahA VidvAn, Sri Devarajacharyar SvAmi from Tirunarayanapuram, sought the refuge of the sacred feet of this Azhagiyasingar. He completed kAlakshepams of [[239]] SrI BhAshyam and other traditional granthams and performed his SaraNAgati. He further wanted to enter in to sanyAsASramam. SrImad Azhagiyasingar performed the upadeSam of presha mantram, gave kAshAya vastram (kAvi vastrams/ochre robes) and the tridaNDam to him. He was given the ASrama tirunAmam of &amp;ldquo;KeSava SaThakopa jIyar&amp;rdquo; by SrImad Azhagiyasingar. Then, Azhagiyasingar commanded his Sishya to create a new commentary for tiruvAimozhi because of his fluency and scholarship in Tamil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 SrI vIrarAghava vedAnta yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/17_SrI_vIrarAghava_vedAnta_yatIndra_m/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/17_SrI_vIrarAghava_vedAnta_yatIndra_m/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born at Thiruvelliyankudi. His avatAra tirunakshatram is Purattasi Sadayam. His ASrama svIkAram as the 17th paTTam Azhagiyasingar was on BahudhAnya VaikAsi (June 1698), Sukla paksha pancami dinam.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SrI Azhagiyasingar started his sancAram from Tirukkudantai and continued up to Srirangam and some divya deSams. He returned to Thiruvellyankudi, where he stayed for an extended period of time. There he was performing a few kaimkaryams and MangaLASAsanams for Maragathavalli tAyAr and SrI Kolavilli Raman. He then returned to Srirangam, and worshipped SrI Ranganathan and SrI Ranganayaki tAyAr. There at Udaiyavar sannidhi, he performed upadeSams for many SishyAs on VedAnta granthams. During his stay at Srirangam, SrI BhAshyam studies were completed twelve times, Bhagavad Vishayam for fifteen times, gItA BhAshyam for ten times and SrImad Rahasyatraya sAram for ten times. He presented several AbharaNams to Namperumal, Azhagiyamanavalan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 SrImannArAyaNa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/18_SrImannArAyaNa_yatIndra_mahAdeSika/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/18_SrImannArAyaNa_yatIndra_mahAdeSika/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar belonging to VeeravalliyAr vamSam was born at Tiruvallur on Purattasi month, ASleshA nakshatram. He ascended to Ahobila maTha AsthAnam on PramAdISa year, thai month (January 1734) Sukla paksha ekAdaSi tithi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar went on sancAram from Thirupputkkuzhi to Kanchipuram and performed his MangaLASAsanam to PeraruLALan and Perumdevi tAyar. From there, he proceeded to Srirangam and on the way, performed MangaLASAsanams to many divya deSa EmperumAns. On arrival at Srirangam after his bath in the River Cauvery and completing his rituals went to the Srirangam temple and performed his MangaLASAsanams for the divya dampatis. Then he went to the daSAvatAra sannidhi. He stayed permanently at daSAvatAra sannidhi and was doing his daily ArAdhanam. There, he was performing kAlakshepams on SrI Bhashyam and other granthams. Koyil Kandatai ANNan SvAmi sought the refuge of SrI Azhagiyasingar and was undergoing kAlakshepams of Azhagiyasingar. During this time, one day Azhagiyasingar said that this daSAvatAra sannidhi is quite comfortable and fit to live (vAsayogyam). On hearing this, Kandatai SvAmi said, &amp;ldquo;The daSAvatAra sannidhi was entrusted to our ancestors by Adi vaN SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan for ArAdhanam and administration. Our family took good care of the sannidhi until now. [[243]] This sannidhi truly belongs to Ahobila maTham. SrImad Azhagiyasingar should take possession of this sannidhi from here on&amp;rdquo;. ANNan SvAmi presented the deeds (mAnyam) for the sannidhi and the Nandavanam linked to the property. He handed over the property to SrImad Azhagiyasingar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 SrI SrInivAsa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/19_SrI_SrInivAsa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/19_SrI_SrInivAsa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born at Thiruvallikkeni and belonged to Nadadur vamSam. His Tirunakshatram is Masi Magham. He entered in to sanyAsa ASramam on Rakshasa samvatsaram, Adi month (July 1735), Krishna paksha navami tithi and ascended the SrI Ahobila maTha ASthAnam.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SrImad Azhagiyasingar started his sancAram from Koyil for northern parts. He went to Thirukkudantai, Thiruvaheendrapuram, Thirukkovalur, Madurantakam, Kanchipuram, Thiruvenkadam and Ahobilam. He performed his MangaLASAsanams for these divya deSa EmperumAns. From Ahobilam, he went again to Tiirumala and then to Gatikachalam, Tiruvallur, Thiruvallikkeni , Thiruneermalai, Thiruvidaventai, Thirukkadanmallai, Thirukkovalur, Srimushnam et al. He worshipped the EmperumAns in these divya deSams. He then went to Thiruppullambhuthamkudi and had his MangaLASAsanam of SrIvalvilli Raman. He stayed there for a few days. SrImad Azhagiyasingar fell ill here and ascended to SrI VaikuNTham in the year, Krodhana, Masi month (February 1746), Sukla paksha caturti tithi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 SrI vIrarAghava yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/20_SrI_vIrarAghava_yatIndra_mahAdeSik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/20_SrI_vIrarAghava_yatIndra_mahAdeSik/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born at Pillaippakkam agrahAram, near Sriperumbhudur, the avatAra sthalam of EmpeumAnAr, on Purattasi mUlam. He ascended the simhAsanam of Ahobila maTham during Krodhana year, Masi month (February 1746 ), Sukla Paksha trtIyai. He started his sancAram from Pullambhuthamkudi to Srirangam, and had his MangaLASAsanam of SrI Ranganathan. From there, he went to Tirunarayanapuram, where he performed his MangaLASAsanam of Yadugiri NaacchiyAr and Tirunarayanan. He stayed there for a few days. Then he continued his sancAram for Thiruvenkadam and there had his MangaLASAsanam for Tiruvenkatamudaiyan. From there, he started to go to Ahobilam. On the way to Ahobilam, SrImad Azhagiyasingar fell ill. He ascended for SrI VaikuNTham on Prabhava year, Panguni month (March 1748), Krishna paksha Saptami tithi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 SrI ParAnkuSa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/21_SrI_ParAnkuSa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/21_SrI_ParAnkuSa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born in TaiyAr agrahAram in Kanchipuram region. He belonged to Vangeepuram BhAradwAja gotram. His tirunakshatram is Panguni Hastam. He entered in to sanayASramam during Prabhava year, Panguni month (March 1748), Krishna paksha sashTi tithi and ascended to SrI Ahobila maTha AsthAnam. He went on sancAram to Ahobilam for the MangalASAsanm of Nava Narasimhars and then proceeded to Tiruvenkadam. After MangaLASAsanam of Lord Srinivasan, he worshipped Lord Govindarajan at Tiruppati (Lower Tiruppati) and Alarmelmangai tAyAr at Thirucchanur. Then he went to Tiruvallur. He had his MangaLASAsanam of SrI Veeraragha Perumal and stayed there for some days. Later, he continued his sancAram to Sriperumbhudur, Perumal Koyil (Kanchipurm), Thiruvaheendrapuram [[247]] and Thirukkudantai and had his MangaLASAsanam of the EmperumAns in these divya deSams. He then went to Srirangam, worshipped SrI Ranganathan and Ranganayaki tAyAr. At Srirangam, he performed upadeSam on sampradAya granthams like SrI BhAshyam at SvAmi DeSikan sannidhi (which is under the administartion of SrI Ahoblia maTham) opposite to SrI Ranganayaki tAyAr sannidhi. He stayed at Srirangam for a few days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 SrImannArAyaNa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/22_SrImannArAyaNa_yatIndra_mahAdeSika/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/22_SrImannArAyaNa_yatIndra_mahAdeSika/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born at GadAdharapuram agrahAram near fertile Tirukkudantai (Kumbakonam) on Adi month, RohiNi Nakshatram. Entering in to sanyASAsramam at Palamedu during ISvara year, Marghazhi month (January 1758), Sukla paksha Pancami tithi, he ascended to the AsthAnam of SrI Ahobila maTham.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From Palamedu, he went on sancAram to Thirunarayanapuram. There, had his bath in Kalyani PushkaraNi. After completing his daily rituals he went to the temple and offered MangaLASAsanams to Thirunarayanan, Yadugiri Naacchiyar, and SrI BhAshyakArar. Then he arrived at Adi vaN SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan&amp;rsquo;s BrundAvanam. He stayed for six months at Thirunarayanapuram. Then on one day after taking leave of the Lord, Thirunarayanan, he started his sancAram to Srirangam for the MangalASAsanam of SrI Ranganathan. Midway to Srirangam, he fell ill at Palamedu village and ascended to Paramapadam on BahudhAnya year, Adi month (August 1758).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 SrI vIrarAghava yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/23_SrI_vIrarAghava_yatIndra_mahAdeSik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/23_SrI_vIrarAghava_yatIndra_mahAdeSik/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born at Thiruvelliyankudi in the month of Ani, UttaraTTAti nakshatram. He entered in to sanyASramam in BahudhAnya samvatsaram, month of Adi (August 1758), KrshNa paksha Pancami dinam and ascended to the throne of SrI maTham. He went on sancAram from Palamedu to Thirunaryanapuram. There he offered his MangaLASAsanams for Thirunarayanan, Yadugiri tAyAr and SrI BhAshyakArar and at the BrundAvanam of SrI Adi vaN SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan. He stayed here for a few days and resumed his sancAram to Ahobilam, Thiruvenkadam, Tiruvallur, Thiruninravur, Thiruvallikkeni, Sriperumbhudur, Perumal Koyil, Thirukkovalur and Thirukkudantai and had his MangalASAsanams of the EmperumAns at these divya deSams. He then went to Srirangam. After a few days of MangaLASAsanam of the Srirangam dampatis, he returned to Thirunarayanapuram. From there, he arrived at PaScimavAhini for the sacred bath and offered his MangaLASAsanam to Sri Ranganathan at Srirangapattinam. Azhagiyasingar fell ill here. Here, he ascended to Paramapadam in SvabhAnu year, thai month (February 1764), Sukla paksha dasami tithi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 SrI ParAnkuSa rAmAnuja yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/24_SrI_ParAnkuSa_rAmAnuja_yatIndra_ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/24_SrI_ParAnkuSa_rAmAnuja_yatIndra_ma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born at Kalyanapuram in Chakravarti vamSam in the month of Chittirai, Punarvasu nakshatram. On SvabhAnu samvatsaram, thai month (February 1763), Sukla paksha Pancami tithi, he accepted SanyAsAsramam at Srirangapattinam and ascended to the AsthAnam. He started his sancAram from Srirangapattinam to Thirunarayanapuram. After MangaLASAsanam of Thirunarayanan, Azhagiyasingar went to Srirangam. He stayed at Srirangam for a few days and was worshiping SrI Ranganathan. Then from Srirangam he started for Ahobilam. On the way to Ahobilam, he had his MangaLASAsanams of EmperumAns of the divya deSams. He arrived at Ahobilam. He took his snAnam at BhavanAsini river and performed MangaLASAsanams of the nine Narasimhars. He stayed at Ahobilam for a few days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 SrI SrInivAsa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/25_SrI_SrInivAsa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/25_SrI_SrInivAsa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born at GadAdharapuram during the Adi month, when SvAti nakshatram was in ascendance. He accepted sanyAsa ASramam on Manmatha samvatsaram, Panguni month (March 1776), Sukla pancami day and ascended the AsthAnam of SrI mATham. In his pUrvASramam, this SvAmi was an expert in sAmAnya sAstrAs like tarkam, VyAkaraNam, mImAmsa etc., and VedAnta SAstrAs. He was also very active practitioner of the daily observance of codes of conduct recommended for five different times of the day (pancakAla parAyaNar). After ascending the throne of SrI maTham, he imparted j&lt;del&gt;nAnam about the four granthams (grantha catushTyams) to his SishyAs, who sought the refuge of his sacred feet. Further, he taught his SishyAs, granthams created by SvAmi DeSikan such as SatadUshaNI, nyAyapariSuddhi, nyAyasiddhAnjanam etc. He shone as the embodiment of j&lt;/del&gt;nAnam, anushThAnam and vairAgyam. His exemplary conduct made a few disgruntled ones very jealous. They approached the one who was responsible for preparing and serving the Azhagiyasingar&amp;rsquo;s daily food (bikshA). Just as AcArya RamAnuja became the object of an attempt to poison him by jealous ones at Srirangam, this Azhagiyasingar became the target of an attempt to poison him through the addition of poisonous material to his food and water. These evil minded people intimidated and tempted the person in charge of the kitchen to mix poison in the food of Azhagiyasingar. So, he agreed to do so. Next day, after serving the poisoned water to Azhagiyasingar, this Kitchen in charge stood before SrImad Azhagiyasingar with tears pouring down from his eyes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 SrI Ranganatha yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/26_SrI_Ranganatha_yatIndra_mahAdeSika/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/26_SrI_Ranganatha_yatIndra_mahAdeSika/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born in Adi month, pUra nakshatram at GadAdharapuram. He belonged to the SrIvatsa gotram. He ascended the AsthAnam of SrI maTham on Prajotpatti year, Kartikai Sukla paksha Pancami tithi (21 November 1811).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He started his sancAram from SrInrusimhapuram (Adanur area) to Adanur, Tirukkudantai divya deSams and reached Srirangam. He had his MangaLASAsanam of the Srirangam divya dampatis. From Srirangam, SrImad Azhagiyasingar continued his sancAram to Thirunarayanapuram. He stayed there for a while, performing MangaLASAsanams of Thirunarayanan, Yadugiri Naacchiyar, SrI BhAshyakArar and Adi vaN SaThakopa jIyar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 SrI vIrarAghava vedAnta yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/27_SrI_vIrarAghava_vedAnta_yatIndra_m/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/27_SrI_vIrarAghava_vedAnta_yatIndra_m/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born on a VaikAsi, aviTTa nakshatram day at GadAdharapuram. He belonged to SrIvatsa gotram. (It was said that the ancestral village is a SrIgrAmam known as Ilanagar in Kanchipuram region and the ancestors seemed to have settled in GadAdharapuram near Kumbakonam). He entered in to sanyAsASramam in SarvadhAri year, Margazhi month, Sukla Pancami tithi (10 January 1829) and ascended to SrI maTham AsthAnam as the 27th pIThadhipati.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 SrI Ranganatha SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/28_SrI_Ranganatha_SaThakopa_yatIndra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/28_SrI_Ranganatha_SaThakopa_yatIndra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born in Tirukkurunkudi. He was born in the month of AvaNi, mUla tirunakshatram. He belonged to SrIvatsa gotram and of Nadadur vamSam. His pUrvASrama name was SrI VAnamAmalAchAryar. This SvAmi and his younger brother, SrI [[266]] Venkatanaryanacharyar were renowned scholars. They both were living in Tirukkurunkudi. They were capable of recalling passages from SrI BhAshyam, SrutaprakASikA, and EDu 36,000 paDi etc., without looking at the original SrI KoSams. Besides having fantastic retention skills on SrI KoSams, they were also excellent in areas like j~nAna sakti, anushThAna balam and intense vairAgyam (dispassion in acquiring worldly riches).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 SrI ParAnkuSa rAmAnuja yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/29_SrI_ParAnkuSa_rAmAnuja_yatIndra_ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/29_SrI_ParAnkuSa_rAmAnuja_yatIndra_ma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born in Lalapettai agrahAram. He belonged to Vajram vamSam. He was born in the month of Chittirai, Chitra nakshartram. He ascended to the AsthAnam of SrI maTham on durmukhi year, Kartikai month, Sukla paksha Navami tithi (17 Nov. 1836).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was an expert in all the SAstrAs (sAmAnya and ViSesha SAstrAs). He was very much detached from aiSvaryam of any kind (virakata). After completing his MangaLASAsanam of Kodandaraman and Janakavalli tAyAr at Madurantakam, he went to Perumal koyil to worship PeraruLALan and Perumdevi tAyAr. He visited other divya deSams in and around Kanchipuram and also SvAmi DeSikan&amp;rsquo;s sannidhi. He then went to the divya deSam of Tirupputkuzhi. There he took his bath in the Jatayu PushkaraNi. After completing his daily rituals, he performed his MangaLASAsanam of the Lord, Vijayaraghavan and Maragathavalli tAyAr.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 SrI SrInivAsa vedAnta yatIndra mahAdesikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/30_SrI_SrInivAsa_vedAnta_yatIndra_mah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/30_SrI_SrInivAsa_vedAnta_yatIndra_mah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born at GadAdharapuram in Marghazhi month when ViSAkha nakshatram was in ascendance. He belonged to SrIvatsa gotram. His pUrvASramam name was SrI. u.vE. Chakravartiyacharyar. He ascended to the simhAsanam of SrI maTham in durmukhi year, Panguni month, Sukla Navami tithi (15th March 1837).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar started his sancAram from Tirupparkkadal and performed MangaLASAsanam of PeraruLALan and Perumdevi tAyAr at Perumal Koyil. He then went to all the divya deSams in Kanchipuram area and worshipped the EmperumAns who all received the MangALASAsanam by the AzhvArs. Azhagiyasingar then performed his MangALASAsanam of SvAmi NigamAnta MahAdeSikan at his avatAra sthalam of tUppul. Then he went to Sriperumbhudur for the MangaLASAsanam of AcArya Ramanuja. He then went to Tiruvallur, Tiruninravur, Tiruvallikkenii, Tiruneermalai, Tiruvidaventai, sthalasayanam (tirukkadanmallai/Mahabalipuram), Madurantakam, Tiruvaheendrapuram and Tirukkudantai. At Tirukkudantai, the AcAryan performed MangaLASAsanam of ArAvamudan with the salutation, &amp;ldquo;piriyAvaDimai ennaik koNDa kuDantai mAlE&amp;rdquo;. He identified KuDantai Perumal as the one who accepted him as His inseparable [[271]] servant. The AcAryan presented a golden kavacam for the Lord&amp;rsquo;s sacred feet and was overwhelmed with joy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 SrImannArAyaNa VedAnta yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/31_SrImannArAyaNa_VedAnta_yatIndra_ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/31_SrImannArAyaNa_VedAnta_yatIndra_ma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born in Adirangam, Karnataka state. He&#xA;belonged to Vinjimoor VamSam. His tirunakshatram is Kartikai&#xA;Magham. He ascended to the AsthAnam of SrI maTham in&#xA;Kartikai month, 24th day, Sukla paksha pancami tithi (7th Dec. 1842).&#xA;He started his sancAram from SrI Nrusimhapuram and performed his&#xA;MangaLASAsanams at the divya desams of Adanur,&#xA;Pullambhuthamkudi, and Tirukkudantai. At Tirukkudantai,&#xA;ArAvamudAzhvAn and ChakrapANi received their MangaLASAsanams.&#xA;He then went to Perumal Koyil for the worship of Devadirajan and&#xA;Perumdevi tAyAr as well as the divya deSa EmperumAns in and around&#xA;Kanchi. Then he arrived Thiruvallur. Here he stayed for a few days&#xA;enjoying the sevA of Sri Veeraraghavan and Kanakavalli tAyAr. He&#xA;presented a big silver elephant (yAnai) vAhanam for Perumal. He then&#xA;www.sadagopan.org AcArya Vaibhavam&#xA;273&#xA;went to Tirumalai and prostrated before SrI Venkatesan and was very&#xA;happy. From Tirumalai, he went to Cholasimhapuram, Thiruvallur,&#xA;Sriperumbudur, Tiruninravur, and Tiruvallikkeni. He then arrived at&#xA;Sri Nrusimhapuram via Tiruvaheendrapuram. He stayed at&#xA;Nrusimhapuram for a few days and blessed the SishyAs with&#xA;kAlakshepams on SrI BhAshyam and other VedAnta granthams. While&#xA;he was here, he created the granthams of SrIi Nrusimha MangaLam&#xA;and SAnga Prapatti nishTha.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After his long stay at SrInrusimhapuram, he visited the agrahAram of Thyagarajapuram on the banks of Cauveri. He found the place peaceful with privacy and fit for a sanyAsi&amp;rsquo;s meditation. He decided to stay there permanently. Here, he fell ill and in ParAbhava year, Panguni month, 19th, Sukla Paksha Caturdasi, Tuesday (30th March, 1847) and attained SrI VaikuNTham.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 SrI vIraraghAva yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/32_SrI_vIraraghAva_yatIndra_mahAdeSik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/32_SrI_vIraraghAva_yatIndra_mahAdeSik/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born in Srivilliputthur in the month of Chittirai, PooraTTAti nakshatram. His ancestral village is Adanur. Hence he was known as &amp;ldquo;Adanur Azhagiyasingar&amp;rdquo;. He ascended the Ahobila maTha SimhAsanam in ParAbhava year, Panguni month, 19th day (30th March, 1847).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Azhagiyasingar left Thyagarajapuram on sancAram to Pullambhuthamkudi (SrInrusimhapuram), AdanUr et al and had his MangaLASAsanam of these EmperumAns. He then went to Srirangam Periya Koyil and after his MangaLASAsanam of Periya Perumal there, went on sancAram to nava tiruppatis of Azhvar Tirunagari etc. After his MangaLASAsanams of the EmperumAns of Vanamamalai and Tirukkurunkudi, he arrived at Madurai. Here, he worshipped at the divya desams of Koodalazhakar, KaLLazhagar and other divya deSa EmperumAns near by. He then returned to Mannargudi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33 SrI SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/33_SrI_SaThakopa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/33_SrI_SaThakopa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born at Parantur agrhAram in Purattasi month, ViSAka nakshatram. He belonged to Vangeepuram vamSam. His pUrvASrama tirunAmam was Vangeepuram VidvAn, SrI VedAntachariyar. He ascended to AsthAnam of SrI Ahoblia maTham in PramAdhISa year, AvaNi month, Sukla Paksha daSami tithi (12th September, 1853).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar after performing MangaLASAsanams of the divya dampatis of Thiruvallur and with Their permission, started his sancAram. He first went to Sriperumbudur and had the MangaLASAsanam of AcArya Ramanuja. Then the jIyar continued his sancAram and worshipped at Perumal Koyil, Madurantakam, Tirukkovalur, Tiruvaheendrapuram, Tirucchittirakoodam, SrimushNam, Tirukkudantai, Tiruvinnagar, Pullambhuthamkudi and AdanUr. After [[277]] this sancAram, he arrived at Srinusimhapuram. Here, he stayed for a long period worshipping the arcA mUrtis in the BrundAvanams of his pUrvAcAryAs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 SrI SaThakopa rAmAnuja yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/34_SrI_SaThakopa_rAmAnuja_yatIndra_ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/34_SrI_SaThakopa_rAmAnuja_yatIndra_ma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was born in the agrahAram of AttippaTTu near Thiruvallur. He was born in his maternal grandfather&amp;rsquo;s house in SrImukha year, Kartikai month when Uttirada Nakshatram was in ascendance (Novmber 1813).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His father and grand father belonged to Injimedu and were linked to the mADabhUshi vamSam. Since this future Azhagiyasingar grew up in his maternal grandfather&amp;rsquo;s house at AttipaTTu, he was hailed as AttipaTTu Azhagiyasingar later. SrImad Injimettu Azhagiyasingar in the Mangala Slokam of his sArabodiini, a commentary on SrImad Rahasyatraya sAram said that 34th paTTam Azhagiyasingar belonged to his vamSam with the salutation &amp;ldquo;madIyakulanAtham&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 SrI Ranganatha yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/35_SrI_Ranganatha_yatIndra_mahAdeSika/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/35_SrI_Ranganatha_yatIndra_mahAdeSika/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The avataAram of this Azhagiyasingar took place in an agrahAram, PonviLainda Kalattur (near Chengalpattu) in the month of VaikASi when the jyeshThA (KeTTai) nakshatram was in ascendance. He belonged to BhAradwAja Gotram (Vangeepuram). His pUrvaSrama tirunAmam was SrI. u. vE. VidvAn Narasimhacharya SvAmi. It was known that during the nirvAka kAlam of AttippaTTu Azhagiyasingar, this SvAmi was doing the SrI kArya kaimkaryam (administrative duties) of the SrI sannidhi. On the niyamanam (command) of SrI SaThakopa Ramanuja yatIndra mahAdeSikan (34th paTTam), this SvAmi took to ascetic order. He ascended to the simhAsanam of the SrI sannidhi in the year CitrabhAnu, Purattasi month, Krshna paksha sashTi tithi, Tuesday (October 3, 1822), when the Rohini nakshatram was in ascendance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36 SrI SrInivAsa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/36_SrI_SrInivAsa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/36_SrI_SrInivAsa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The avatAram of this Azhagiyasingar was at the agrahAram of Parantur in Kanchipuram region, in the month of Adi when Pushya nakshatram was in ascendance. His pUrvASrama tirunAmam was SrI. u. vE. VidvAn Vangeepuram Rangacharya SvAmi. He ascended the simhAsanam of SrI sannidhi in the year SarvadhAri, Adi month (31st), Monday when SvAti nakshatram was in ascendance (13 August 1888).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar staying in Thiruvallur for a long time was performing MangaLAsAsanam of SrI Veeraraghavan and Kanakavalli tAyAr. He was also rendering kAlakshepam on granthams. He travelled to Sriperumbudur and performed MangaLASAsanam to EmperumAnAr. He then went on sancAram to Kanchipuram Perumal Koyil, Madurantakam, Thiruvaheendrapuram, Thirukkudantai, Pullambutamkudi, Adanur and other divya deSams and had his MangaLAsAsanam of the EmperumAns and arrived at Srirangam. He performed MangaLASAsanam to SrI Ranganathan and SrI RanganAcchiyar and daSAvatAra Perumal. He stayed in Srirangam for a few days. He then travelled to PancamAdevi and SuNDapAlayam agrahArams near Srirangam. There, he was rendering kAlakshepam on SrI BhAshya granthams to his SishyAs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>37 SrI vIrarAghava SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdesikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/37_SrI_vIrarAghava_SaThakopa_yatIndra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/37_SrI_vIrarAghava_SaThakopa_yatIndra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;avatAram&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar’s avatAram took place at Pillaipakkam agrahAram near Sriperumbudur. He was born in the year Krodhi, month of Masi (March 1845) when the Pushya nakshatram was in ascendance. He belonged to Kausika gotram in the KomAndUr Ilayavalli vamSam. His father&amp;rsquo;s tirunAmam was SrI Veeraraghavacharya SvAmi. This Azhagiyasingar as an expert in Veda VedAntam strictly adhered to performing all the good deeds and anushThAnam (rituals). His mother&amp;rsquo;s name was Kanakavalli, daughter of iLanagar Tirumalai kaTTam Srinivasatatacharya SvAmi, a paramaikAnti (one who is devoted only to Perumal and who does not need anything from Him except doing kaimkaryam to the Lord) with unblemished attributes. This Azhagiyasingar&amp;rsquo;s pUrvASrama tirunAmam was SaptatantravAcaspati VidvAn Gopalacharya SvAmi. He had two brothers and five sisters. He had the upanayana samskArams at the appropriate age and was studying VedAdhyayanam, kAvyam, nATakam etc., from his father. Every day he along with his brothers used to take bath in the village tank, veppangkANi, completing his daily rituals, walk back to his home reciting brahmayaj~na praSnam. The elders of the village seeing them used to say that they are fortunate to see them which are like seeing vAmana, trivikrama avatArams of the Lord together at one place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38 SrI SrinivAsa SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/38_SrI_SrinivAsa_SaThakopa_yatIndra_m/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/38_SrI_SrinivAsa_SaThakopa_yatIndra_m/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The avatAram of this Azhagiyasingar took place at Thirukkudantai in the year SiddhArti, thai month, dvAdaSI tithi, Friday when ArudrA nakshatram was in ascendance (January 1860). His pUvASrama name was Thirukkudantai ILanagar Gadadharapuram SrIvatsAngam VidvAn SrI u. vE. Chakravarthi Venkatacharya SvAmi. He was an expert in tarka SAstram. He had his VedAnta kAlakshepam with Pillaipakkam Azhagiyasingar and received his blessings. He was very wealthy too. Some of his ancestors who were great scholars have administered the SrI sannidhi AsthAnam. Thus he had the distinction of being a descendant of a noble clan, scholarly person and blessed with abundant wealth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>39 SrI ParAnkuSa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/39_SrI_ParAnkuSa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/39_SrI_ParAnkuSa_yatIndra_mahAdeSikan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The avatAram of this Azhagiyasingar took place at Rajamannarkoyil (Mannargudi) in the VaikAsi month, when BharaNi nakshatram was in ascendance. He belonged to the vamSam of Uruppattur Chakravarthi. He ascended the simhAsanam of the AsthAnam in the year Saumya, VaikAsi month 8th, Sukla dvitIyai tithi, Friday (21st May 1909) when Mrugaseersha nakshatram was in ascendance. In his pUrvASramam, he was popularly known as VyAkaraNam RangAcharya SvAmi. As per the direction of the Thirukkudantai Azhagiyasingar (38th paTTam), he took to ascetic order at SrI Nrusimhapuram. After ascending the simhAsanam of the SrI sannidhi, this Azhagiyasingar performed MangaLASAsanam of the EmperumAn at PuLLambudamkudi and Adanur. Taking leave of the EmperumAns of these divya deSams, he went to Mannargudi. Staying there permanently, he was performing MangaLASAsanam to Rajagopalan. He renovated the maTham at Mannargudi. This Azhagiyasingar got made to a Silver MaNTapam for SrI LakshmInrusimhan. The walls of the northern prakAram of Thiruvallur Veeraraghavan sannidhi was constructed during the time of this Azhagiyasingar. He was performing panca samskAram, bharanyAsam and grantha kAlakshepams to his SishyAs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40 SrI Ranganatha SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/40_SrI_Ranganatha_SaThakopa_yatIndra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/40_SrI_Ranganatha_SaThakopa_yatIndra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The avatAram of this Azhagiyasingar took place at an agrahAram known as Karukkuricchi on the banks of Tambrabarani River in the year Virodhikrut, Margazhi month (December 1851) when the ViSAka nakshatram was in ascendance. He belonged to Vangeepuram vamSam. His pUrvASrama tirunAmam was SrI. u. vE. VidvAn Vangeepuram Venkatakrishnamachaiyar. He took to ascetic order in [[331]] the year PramAthi, 8th day of Chittirai month, Pushya nakshartram, Monday (17 April 1913), and ascended to SrI maTham AsthAnam. After Mannargudi Azhagiyasingar (39th paTTam) attained Paramapadam in the year Raakshasa, VaikAsi month (May 1915), this Azhagiyasingar offered MangaLASAsanam of Sri RajagopAlan. He then took leave of the Lord and started his sancAram with SrI LakshmInrusimhan. He performed MangaLASAsanam of the EmperumAns in the south at Srirangam, Thirumalirumcholai, Azhwar Thirunagari etc., and then to Northern side up to Hyderabad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>41 SrIlakshmInrsimha SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/41_SrIlakshmInrsimha_SaThakopa_yatInd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/41_SrIlakshmInrsimha_SaThakopa_yatInd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The avatAram of this Azhagiyasingar took place in the agrahAram of Karukkuricchi on the banks of Thamrabarani River in the year Ananda, Margazhi month (December 1854) when the Poorattadi nakshatram was in ascendance. He belonged to vAdhUa gotram. His pUrvASrama tirunAmam was SrI. u. vE. VidvAn taTTai Gopala RamabhadrchAryar. Taking to ascetic order in the year dundubhi, 4th day of thai month (17 January 1923) he ascended to the AsthAnam. Of all those Azhagiyasingars before him, he was the oldest to head the AsthAnam. Despite his old age, he was performing all the nityakarmAnushThanam with high priority and reverence. He conducted discourses at frequent intervals for the entire duration of his nirvAkam as the head of the AsthAnam. Besides the discourses on grantha catushTyam, he rendered kAlakshepam on SatadUshaNI, [[333]] nyayasiddhAnjanam and other granthams amidst the gathering of learned scholars of repute. He did his sancAram in the south from Thuvariman to Setu (Thirupullani) and in the north up to Tiruppati. He stayed permanently at daSAvatAra sannidhi in Srirangam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>42 SrI SrIranga SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/42_SrI_SrIranga_SaThakopa_yatIndra_ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/42_SrI_SrIranga_SaThakopa_yatIndra_ma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The avatAram of this Azhagiyasingar took place at Yaj~navedyagrahAram, popularly known as Injimedu agrahAramm established by the 6th paTTam Azhagiyasingar. He belonged to BhAradvAja gotram of AttippaTTu Azhagiyasingar. His avatAram was in the year BahudhAnya, month of thai when the UttirAda nakshartram was in ascendance (21 January 1879). His pUrvASrama tirunAmam was SrI InjimEdu mADabhUshi SrI. u. vE. VidvAn Ranganathachariyar. [[335]] He learnt sAmAnya SAstras at Thirukkudantai, Mysore, Kasi and Tiruppati. He possessed extraordinary competency in putting forth his views though his mastery of tarka SAastras. He had his kAlakshepam under SvarNam SrI Krishnamacharya mahAdeSikan, popularly known as SrI Mushnam SvAmi, the SishyA of Pillaipakkam Azhagiyasingar. Our SvAmi used to recite the mantrAs initiated to him by SrI Mushnam SvAmi. He was doing noble deeds and lived a life focussed on the liberation of the soul. Thirukkudantai Azhagiyasingar (38th paTTam) used to compliment and praise our SvAmi’s mastery and proficiency in VedAnta SAstrAs. SrIlakshmInrsimha SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan (41st paTTam Azhagiyasingar) had appointed our SvAmi as the AsthAna VidvAn. As directed by 41st paTTam Azhagiyasingar, our SvAmi authored the granthams, &amp;ldquo;uktinishThAbharaNam&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;nyAsanishThA-mImAmsA&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;uktinishThabharNodyodayam&amp;rdquo;. During his AsthAna time, he composed an elaborate commentary on SrImadrahasyatrayasAram namely &amp;ldquo;sArabodhinI&amp;rdquo;. He also authored the following granthams:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>43 SrI vIrarAghva SaThakopa yatIndra mahAdeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/43_SrI_vIrarAghva_SaThakopa_yatIndra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/43_SrI_vIrarAghva_SaThakopa_yatIndra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Azhagiyasingar was the eldest son of SrI. u. vE. VidvAn ParuttippaTTu Vangeepuram Thiruvenkatacharyar of Devanarvilagam near Oppiliappan Kovil. The avatAram of this Azhagiyasingar took place in the year Plava, Kartigai month when the Poorada nakshatram was in ascendance (year 1901). The pUrvaSrama tirunAmam of this Azhagiyasingar was SrI u. vE. VidvAn Lakshminrusimhachariyar SvAmi. He passed in tarka Siromani course from Thiruvaiyaru college. Even during his younger age, his acumen and intellect were praised by elder scholars. SvAmi had rendered kAlakshpem to several disciples during his pUrvASramam. In short, this SvAmi was conducting tiruvArAdhanam and kainkaryam by treating his home as a small maTham. He used to say, &amp;ldquo;The house, garden, agricultural lands and other wealth which the others mention as mine does not belong to me. They are the property of EmperumAn Kannan only. He has appointed me as a trustee and I am performing my duties with this thought embedded in my mind&amp;rdquo;. He led a selfless simple life of deep devotion and determination is performing the rituals without any compromise. He was an example to other scholars and vidvAns and was performing [[338]] the ritualistic chores five times a day without fail. He was the Principal of the Madurantakam Veda Prabandha School.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>44 SrI VedAnta deSika yatIndra MahadeSikan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/44_SrI_VedAnta_deSika_yatIndra_Mahade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/ahobilam/44_SrI_VedAnta_deSika_yatIndra_Mahade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mukkur Srimad Azhagiasingar—A Sage beyond Compare By SrI K. Sadagopa Iyengar, Editor, SrI Nrsimhapriya (English)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Born at the holy village of Mukkur in North Arcot (presently Tiruvannamalai) District on 23.8.1895 (Manmatha Samvatsaram Avani Hastam) to Sri Ranganathacharya Swami and Smt. Ranganayaki Ammangar as the first of five children, Sri Rajagopalacharya (as Mukkur Srimad Azhagiasingar was known in his purvashramam) underwent upanayanam and Pancha Samskaram at the hands of his father, a Vedic scholar, having performed adhyayanam. He was born in the holy star of Hastam, in the Bharadvaja Gotra and Tattai Vamsam. He studied Kavyas and Natakas under Thaiyar Srinivasacharya Swami and later went to Srimushnam, where he performed Vedadhyayanam under Ghanapati Krishnamacharya Swami, continuing his Kavya studies under Swarnam Krishnamacharya Swami. As his father shifted to Mannargudi, Sri Rajagopalacharya too went there and studied Vyakaranam under “Vyakaranam” Krishnamacharya Swami, while continuing his Vedadhyayanam. He was the first student at the MRR Kottur Rangaswamy Mudaliar Patasala, studying under such eminent vidvans like Thillayambur Sri Chakravarthyacharya Swami, at whose feet he absorbed Tarka and Vedanta Shastras and also the art of delivering discourses. He underwent samashrayanam again from the 40th Srimad Azhagiasingar, considering the sanctity of Sri Sannidhi Shankha and Chakra. He learnt Divya Prabandam from Kasi Sri Kuppuswamy Iyengar Swami. He performed numerous services to Sri Rajagopala Swami of Mannargudi. Even during his studentship, Swami used to attend Vidvat Sadas at various places and impressed scholars with his precocious wisdom. Swami entered the holy state of matrimony at the age of 18, wedding Janakavalli Ammangar of the Chetlur lineage, who proved in every way worthy of Swami and the abode of all womanly virtues. In course of time, two daughters and a son were born to Swami. Swami had to take care of his large family of parents, brothers and children, with the meagre resources available. Swami was summoned for the service of the 40th Pontiff, who was camping at Hyderabad and this marked the beginning of a saga of selfless service to Sri Ahobila Matham and Srimad Azhagiasingars. Swami performed intimate kainkaryams to HH, whose travels were far-flung and rigorous. When HH returned to Thuvariman on the banks of Vaigai near Madurai, his health deteriorated and he could not indicate his choice of a successor. However, our Swami, who knew the mind of HH, declared that Karukurichi Sri Gopala &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sadagopan.org&#34;&gt;www.sadagopan.org&lt;/a&gt; AcArya Vaibhavam 341 Ramabhadracharya Swami was HH’s choice as successor. As there were different opinions, when HH’s confirmation was sought, he raised his head, though feebly, in affirmation. Swami immediately travelled to Karukurichi and brought Sri Gopala Ramabhadracharya Swami for assuming the spiritual throne of Sri Ahobila Matham, displaying admirable presence of mind. With his growing reputation and popularity as a Upanyasaka, Swami was very much in demand all over India. Later, he started performing Aradhanam at the Kanchi branch of Sri Ahobila Mutt, enlightening several Sri Vaishnavas with kalakshepam on sampradayic lore. He was blessed with Bharasamarpanam by the 41st Pontiff at Tiruvallur, who was later succeeded by Injimedu Srimad Azhagiasingar. Mukkur Sri Rajagopalacharya was appointed Astana Vidvan and continued to spread sampradayic wisdom far and wide, during which period he shifted his family to Tiruvallur. Swami continued his services under the stewardship of the 43rd Jeeyar, Devanarvilaham Srimad Azhagiasingar and accompanied him on his sancharam to Hyderabad and further north. When HH was travelling towards Ayodhya, he halted at Naimisaranyam, where he was affected by the severe cold, despite which he continued his rigorous anushttanam. This made him severely ill and he passed away at Naimisaranyam. As per the wishes of Srimad Azhagiasingar and the entreaties of assembled disciples, Mukkur Rajagopalacharya Swami assumed the ochre robes and ascended the spiritual throne of Sri Ahobila Matham at Naimisaranyam as the 44th Jeeyar on 27th Nov. 1957 (Hemalambi Kartikai Sravanam), with the tirunamam, SrivanSatakopa Sri Vedanta Desika Yatindra Mahadesikan. After performing the kainkaryam of the 43rd Jeeyar in an exemplary manner and building his brindavanam at Naimisaranyam, the 44th Jeeyar resumed travel with Sri Malolan and went to Pushkar at the request of Ramkumar Sethji of Calcutta, where he delighted audiences with his discourses in Sanskrit and Hindi. Proceeding south via Kota, HH reached Tirumala, where he observed his first Chaturmasya Sankalpam and started delivering kalakshepams on Sri Bhashyam and Srimad Rahasyatrayasaram. After a long and rigorous sancharam that covered most of the villages in Tamilnadu and Kerala and being worshipped by two Maharajas of Kerala, HH reached Mukkur via Srirangam and camped there for long. His 60th and 70th tirunakshatrams were celebrated at Kanchi and Ahobilam respectively, with the latter event marked by HH’s construction and consecration of a Rajagopuram at Ahobilam Sri Prahladavaradan Sannidhi. The silver jubilee of the Malola Vidvat Sadas, an annual congregation of eminent scholars for discussions in sampradaya granthas like Sri Bhashya, was also celebrated at Ahobilam. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sadagopan.org&#34;&gt;www.sadagopan.org&lt;/a&gt; AcArya Vaibhavam 342 HH had acquired prodigious scholarship in Sri Bhashyam and other sampradaya works and delighted in asking scholars apparently unanswerable questions during the Vidvat sadas, to which he himself would later furnish the answers. HH authored several works on Sri Bhashya, like Bhashyarttha Padya Malika, apart from several Stotras like the LakshmiNrisimha Karavalamba Stotram. One of the qualities which was inherent in him and came to the fore often, was his compulsive generosity, which made him share whatever he had with the needy and destitute. As a result, in his purvashramam, he would give away all that he had, often going hungry. Such selflessness and generosity continued after he assumed sanyasam and literally thousands benefited from his largesse. Like Koorattazhwan, he could not bear the sight of anyone suffering and would do whatever he could immediately, even at personal cost, to provide relief. And his penchant for feeding people was legendary; his concern extended not only to people, irrespective of caste, creed or colour, but also to animals. During these years, new Mutt branches with temples and wedding halls were constructed at Bombay, Hyderabad, Ahobilam, etc. The temple tank at Tiruvallur fell barren and HH devised an ingenious scheme of a tank within a tank, which ensures till date water for the tiruvaradhanam and festivals of Sri Vaidya Viraraghava Swami. A few years after his satabhishekam was celebrated by disciples at Kanchi, HH was blessed with a dream in which Sri Ranganatha commanded the Pontiff to build a tall tower in the place of the (incomplete) Mottai gopuram at the southern entrance to Srirangam. In implicit obedience, he took up this mammoth task when he was 85 and despite facing problems galore in securing approvals, dealing with opposition from various misguided sources, assembling men, money and materials, etc., HH put up a tall and imposing Rajagopuram towering 236 feet into the sky with thirteen tiers, samprokshanam for which was performed in 1987 in the presence of the President of India Sri R. Venkataraman, the Chief Minister of Tamilnadu Sri MGR and a host of other dignitiaries and Vaidikas. HH was 92 then, but used to personally inspect construction work daily by visiting the gopuram and riding up to the topmost tiers in a freight lift! The completion of the gopuram marked the completion of HH’s life mission, one might say. Though he continued to perform tiruvaradhanam to Sri Malolan daily, age began to tell on him and with foresight, he appointed Villivalam Sri Krishnamacharya Swami as his successor, who assumed sanyasa ashrama in Oct. 1991. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sadagopan.org&#34;&gt;www.sadagopan.org&lt;/a&gt; AcArya Vaibhavam 343 And eager to perform kainkaryam to Paramapadanathan, HH left for his eternal abode on Sunday, 16th Aug 1992, (Bhadrarpada Krishna Paksha Triteeya) at the age of 97, lamented by millions of disciples who had been blessed by him with Samashrayanam, bharasamarpanam, good advice, financial assistance and what not. He now rests in the Brindavanam at Dasavatara Sannidhi, right at the feet of his Bharanyasa Acharya, the 41st Srimad Azhagiasingar. Men with such courage, resoluteness, humane nature, generosity, scholarship and dispassion are extremely rare. Mukkur Srimad Azhagiasingar trod this earth like a colossus for a century and benefited not only Sri Ahobila Matham and its disciples, but the entire humanity, with his compassion for all. He was equally at home with top-notch scholars of the Sampradaya, as with the illiterate and downtrodden, addressing the suffering of all with an even and open hand and a large heart. He was an inspiration for scholars, who derived so much wisdom from him and equally attractive to children, whom he used to pose arithmetical problems to. His kainkaryams were so huge that they are beyond the contemplation, leave alone emulation, of mortals. Works authored by this Azhagiasingar: Injimedu Srimad Azhagiasingar Mangalam, Sri LakshmiNrisimha Karavalamba Stotram, Saareerakadhikarana Krama Bodhini, Brahmasutraarttha Padya Maalika, Visishtadvaita Siddhanta Tatva Sangaraham, Sri LakshmiNrisimha Prapatti, Dayaasaagara Satakam, Panchamrita Stotram, Mangalamaalika (on Srimad Azhgagiasingars), hundreds of Arulmozhis in Sri NrisimhaPriya, etc. Kainkaryams of Mukkur Srimad Azhagiasingar Brindavan at Naimisaranyam for Devanarvilagam Srimad Azhagiasingar, Sri Varadarajan Sannidhi at Mukkur, Sri Nammazhwar Sannidhi at Kanchi, Matham at Pullabuthangudi, Thayar Sannidhi at Injimedu, Stone mandapam at the avatara sthalam of Injimedu Srimad Azhagiasingar, Rajagopuram at Ahobilam, Hrittaapanaasini Pushkarini and Chaitra Brahmotsava Mandapam at Tiruvallur, Sri LakshmiNarayanan Sannidhi and Kalyana Mandapam at Chembur (Mumbai), Moolavar pratishttai at Pullabhuthangudi and Tiruvadanur, Sri Matham at Hyderabad and Tiruvaheendrapuram, Rajagopuram at Pullabhuthangudi, etc. And the crowning glory for his kainkaryams was the towering Rajagopuram at Srirangam. Srimad Azhagiasingar’s Thanian: Sri Ranganatha Satakopa Yatindra drishtam LakshmiNrisimha Satajit karunaika paatram  [[344]] Sriranga Veeraraghuraat Satakopa hridyam Vedanta Desika Yatindram aham prapadye.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
