[Commentator reciting Sanskrit Shloka]: Apavitrah pavitro va sarvavasthangato'pi va...
In this video, I will attempt to dispel a common misconception held by the Madhva community regarding Srivaishnavas.
First, let us hear what one of their prominent scholars, Mahuli Acharya, has to say on this matter.
[Mahuli Acharya]: They claim that Chaitanya is Narayana himself manifest.
They say Narayana took this form as a servant (dasa) to demonstrate to the world how a true servant of God should live.
They call it a Purnavatara (complete incarnation) or a direct incarnation of Narayana.
However, from the lineage of Rajendra Tirtha and according to the Srimadacharya (Madhva) tradition, this is not accepted by any Vaishnava.
Therefore, that Gaudiya Sampradaya's theory is distant from us. In reality, our tradition does not view him as Narayana.
[Commentator]: So far, we have heard that followers of Chaitanya Mahaprabhu view him as an incarnation of Narayana.
He states that this is not accepted in their tradition and that he is not a Purnavatara.
We will discuss this further. Now, let's hear what he says about the Swaminarayan tradition.
[Mahuli Acharya]: Regarding the Swaminarayan Sampradaya—they maintain that Swaminarayan is Narayana himself.
They propound this theory, but this incarnation is not mentioned anywhere in the Puranas or the Mahabharata.
Therefore, it should not be considered an incarnation of the Supreme Lord (Paramatma). Thus, their theory is far from our principles.
Though they are Vishnu-bhaktas (devotees of Vishnu), they believe Krishna manifest as Swaminarayan.
Unless one understands which are true incarnations and which are not, or who is divinely empowered (Avesha), there is no salvation (Moksha).
This has been explicitly stated by Srimadacharya in the Tantrasara. Therefore, we must understand these theories systematically.
Even Prithu Chakravarthy is not a direct incarnation; he is an Aveshavatara (empowered incarnation). This is how we must understand it.
The same applies to Lord Balarama. In the Ramanuja (Srivaishnava) tradition, they claim Balarama is a Purnavatara.
But for us, Balarama is not an incarnation of Paramatma; he is an Aveshavatara of the Supreme Lord.
While Ramanuja's followers view Balarama as a direct avatar, we hold that he is an Avesha (divine possession).
They say Chaitanya is an avatar; we say he is neither an avatar nor an Avesha.
They say Swaminarayan is an avatar; we say he is neither. Regarding Balarama, he is mentioned in Puranas, but not as a direct avatar.
Prithu, Balarama, and others are not God himself but possess divine empowerment. Srimadacharya has decided this in his Shastras.
[Commentator]: There are several flaws in what has been stated here.
How can one decide if a person is a Purnavatara, Aveshavatara, Swarupavesha, or Shakti-avesha?
Is it enough to just read one or two Puranas or the Mahabharata?
If one does not study properly, mistakes occur. Madhvas accept the Pancharatra Agamas.
In those Agamas, it is clearly mentioned who is an Aveshavatara, what kind of Avesha it is, and who is worshipable.
Deciding without looking at these sources is incorrect. I am not saying that everyone thinks like Mahuli Acharya, but his current conclusion is flawed.
Let's first understand how many types of incarnations there are. According to Srivaishnava orthodox views, which follow the Agamas...
Incarnations can be Purnavatara or Aveshavatara. A Purnavatara is when the Lord Himself descends in a body.
He takes a form like a human or an animal to uplift the world. This is the Lord's direct presence.
In some cases, the Lord enters after a soul with his divine form; this is called SvarupAveshavatara.
In other instances, He doesn't enter with his full form but empowers a soul with specific divine energies (Shakti) to perform tasks.
This is called Shakti-aveshavatara. Thus, there are three main types.
These are all explained very clearly in the Pancharatra Agamas.
While Mahuli Acharya's intent may be sincere, he has not followed the scriptural evidence accurately.
I have not seen any Srivaishnava text claiming Balarama is a Purnavatara in the way he alleges.
Representing another's school of thought accurately is a scholar's duty. He has failed to do so.
He claims Srivaishnavas lack valid evidence, but the Madhva view itself contradicts scriptures like the Sattvata Samhita.
Another point: Ramanuja, Lakshmana, and Ananta are fancied as three forms of the same soul by Srivaishnavas.
There is a famous verse: "Anantah prathamam rupam lakshmanascha tatah param..." confirming this popular perception.
So his claim that we view Balarama as a Purnavatara like Vishnu is unproven. It is an Avesha.
Scholars like Mahuli Acharya should represent opposing views with more care.
In the Madhva view, Vyasa is considered a Purnavatara. I understand that to them, Vyasa is Vishnu Himself.
But in Srivaishnavism, based on the Agamas, we see Vyasa as a soul empowered (Anupravishta) by Vishnu.
So, he might as well pick that in order to highlight difference. There was no need to cite examples like Balarama or Prithu Chakravarthy to make his point.
Now, regarding Chaitanya Mahaprabhu and Swaminarayan not being avatars because they aren't in Puranas...
Has the Lord ever said that He *only* incarnates if mentioned in history or Puranas? No.
In the Gita, He promises: "Yada yada hi dharmasya glanir bhavati bharata..." He manifests whenever righteousness declines.
His argument that they aren't avatars lacks scriptural proof. He should provide better evidence.
It seems Madhva scholars have not analyzed the Pancharatra Agamas correctly, which clearly distinguish these forms.
The Sattvata Samhita explicitly lists Brahma, Shiva, Vyasa, Arjuna, Parashurama, and Kubera as empowered souls (AveshAvatAra-s).
It says they are souls empowered for specific tasks and are not to be worshipped by those seeking liberation (Mumukshus) as the Supreme God.
They are all 'Avishta' (entered/possessed) for a purpose. Worshipping them as the Supreme is prohibited for moxa-seekers.
Direct incarnations like Rama and Krishna are like one lamp lighting another; there is no difference in their divine nature.
They are worshipable by Mumukshus for crossing the ocean of birth and death. This is the clear stance of the Sattvata Samhita.
The Madhva view, which contradicts this scriptural evidence, cannot be considered authoritative on this specific point.
Even according to their own system, the Pancharatra Agamas are pramANa-s. Among them, the Sattvata Samhita is considered part of the 'Ratnatraya' (the three gems).
Therefore, within the hierarchy of Pancharatra texts, the Sattvata Samhita holds a position of high authority.
Some dissident shrIvaiShNava scholars try to resolve these contradictions by using the 'Kalpabheda' theory—suggesting Vyasa was a direct avatar in one cosmic age but empowered in another.
However, their own Acharyas, like Parashara Bhattar, have accepted the direct words of the Sattvata Samhita.
If there are any errors in my presentation, please let me know in the comments. My goal was to clarify the Srivaishnava stance. Namo Namaha.