<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Contra shaiva on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Contra shaiva on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HariM harantam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/hariM_harantam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/hariM_harantam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;harim-harantam-shruti----an-analysis&#34;&gt;Harim Harantam Shruti &amp;ndash; An Analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is pertinent to mention this particular shrutivAkya which has been debated by vaishnavas and shaivas. This shruti occurs in the taittiriyaAraNyaka, as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;hariM harantam anuyanti devAH | vishvasyeshAnaM vR^iShabhaM matInAM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This shrutivAkya is interesting because it lends itself to many possible interpretations due to the grammatical possibilities of “hariMharantam..”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, the shaiva interpretations are wrong both grammatically as well as from the perspective of shruti, and there is no need to address them considering statements like “eko ha vanArAyaNaAseetna brahma nEShAna”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ishvara gItA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/Ishvara-gItA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/Ishvara-gItA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;prelude-to-the-ishvara-gita---jnana-yoga&#34;&gt;Prelude to the Ishvara Gita - Jnana Yoga&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We will soon be publishing a translation of the Ishvara Gita from the Kurma Purana on this blog. As it is a complicated text, we thought it would be wise to release a series of smaller articles as preludes, to enable an understanding of the fundamentals that the work is based on. This is the first of the preludes. Here, we will explain what Jnana-Yoga is according to the Shastra, as it is relevant to the Ishvara Gita.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JnAnasambandha tirumangai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/jnAna-sambandha_tirumangai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/jnAna-sambandha_tirumangai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;thirugnana-sambandhar-and-thirumangai-azhwar&#34;&gt;Thirugnana Sambandhar and Thirumangai Azhwar&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is well-known that Thirugnana Sambandhar was a great Shiva bhakta, an accomplished tamil poet and the Thevaram contains his devotional outpourings on Shiva. The time period of Shri Thirumangai Azhwar, the last of the great azhwars, coincided with that of Sambandhar and their paths crossed. This write-up aims to bring out the events of that meeting and the consequences thereof.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The traditional narration of the incident is summarized in the following blog – &lt;a href=&#34;https://guruparamparai.wordpress.com/2013/01/23/thirumangai-azhwar&#34;&gt;https://guruparamparai.wordpress.com/2013/01/23/thirumangai-azhwar&lt;/a&gt; . Quoting from that blog,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KarNa parva shiva stuti</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/karNa-parva-shiva-stuti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/karNa-parva-shiva-stuti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;shiva-stuti-in-karna-parvan&#34;&gt;Shiva Stuti in Karna Parvan&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SHIVA STUTI IN KARNA PARVA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we have already proven with the Shiva Sahasranama, any alleged instances in the mahAbhArata showing shiva as Brahman are but attempts at interpolations. However, there is a genuine stuti occurring in the karNa parva, just prior to the description of Tripura samhAra. Here, the devas, acting on the instructions of Brahma, seek refuge in Shiva for destroying the asurAs. There is nothing anomalous in this; as srI krishNa himself says, the devas beginning with Indra seek shelter of Shiva who in turn seeks refuge in Brahma, who in turn seeks vAsudevA as his refuge. Thus a simple hierarchy of IndrAdi devatA &amp;lt; shiva &amp;lt; brahma &amp;lt; nArAyaNa is established. Even the nArAyaNasUkta is in that descending order “sa brahma sa siva sEndra” and hanuman describes these three devas in the same descending order in the rAmAyaNa, also saying that srI rAma is superior to all 3 of them single or combined.  Brahma is of course, the most exalted jivAtma in the Universe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keshi sUkta sharabha narasiMha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/keshi-sUkta-sharabha-narasiMha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/keshi-sUkta-sharabha-narasiMha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;keshi-suktam-and-the-sharabha-narasimha-episode&#34;&gt;Keshi Suktam and the Sharabha-Narasimha episode&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The keSi sUkta is a stuti of bhagavAn as the antaryAmin of Brahma and Rudra in the context of the samudra mathanam incident. In that charitra, bhagavAn appeared in various manifestations as Ajita (who churned the poison), Kurma (who upheld the Mandara), Dhanvantri (who appeared with medicine), the indweller of Rudra (who drank the poison), Mohini (who misled the asurAs) and Vishnu (who married srI mahAlakshmi).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KRShNa prays to shiva</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/kRShNa-prays-to-shiva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/kRShNa-prays-to-shiva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;prayers-of-sri-krishna-to-shiva&#34;&gt;Prayers of Sri Krishna to Shiva&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SRI KRISHNA STUTI (Part 1) - INTRODUCTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bhagavad rAmAnuja muni, known as yatirAjA, is like Trivikrama in that he conquered the 3 worlds with his unassailable philosophy of Vishishtadvaita Vedanta. The nectar of his lotus feet manifested in the form of Acharya Nampillai whose Eedu vyAkhyAnam can be compared to the Ganga flowing from the lotus feet of sriman nArAyaNa. Just as Shiva bore the Ganga on his head, the Eedu vyAkhyAnam reached Swami Manavala Mamunigal, the King of SattvikAs, who imparted its sweet meanings in a manner that can be understood by all AstikAs. Just as Bhagiratha performed a penance to bring the Ganga to this world, my Acharyas like srI PBA Swami and srI rangarAjAchAriar, worshipped Swami manavAla mAmunigal and distributed the meanings of Eedu to the laypersons such as myself. With their blessings, I write now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manyu sUktam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/manyu-sUktam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/manyu-sUktam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;manyu-suktam----a-sri-vaishnava-commentary&#34;&gt;Manyu Suktam &amp;ndash; A Sri Vaishnava commentary&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MANYU SUKTAM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(contributed by our Srivaishnava bandhu Shri Narayanan. This essay was posted in parts in the &amp;ldquo;Sri Ramanuja&amp;rdquo; Yahoo group.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sri Manyu Sukta is one of the more important suktams occurring the Rg Veda. The rishi is known as tApasa manyu, the devatA is srI Lakshmi narasimha (Manyu) and the meter is trishtup/jagatI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a common misconception that some particular devas like Indra are mentioned several times in the veda, whereas Vishnu is mentioned relatively less number of times. To dispel this illusion, a reading of this suktam will help. The truth is that, ALL the suktams are talking about srI hari only. When the veda says, “Bhagavan Indra, the Slayer of Vrtra”, it does not refer to the deva known as Indra who killed the asura vrtra. Rather, it refers to parabrahman sriman nArAyaNa, who is known as Indra, which has the meaning of “foremost/excellent/best) and who is the slayer of the covering (vrtra) called prakrti/ajnana/andhakAra”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mbh interpolations</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/mbh-interpolations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/mbh-interpolations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interpolations in the Mahabharata denying Vishnu&amp;rsquo;s supremacy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DETERMINING THE AUTHENCITY OF CERTAIN PORTIONS IN THE MAHABHARATA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When discussing the Parabrahman of Sruti, Smriti, IthihAsa and purAnA, it becomes clear upon a cursory read that it is only sriman nArAyaNa  who has been praised by all the devas, rishis, jnAnis and even by some asuras (shishupAla, mAricha and even rAvaNa have admitted it) as the possessor of infinitely auspicious attributes, the husband of shrI, the foremost of gods, who alone is worthy of worship, the sole bestower of moksha and the master of all jIvas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NIlarudra sUktam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/nIlarudra-sUktam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/nIlarudra-sUktam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;nilarudra-sukta&#34;&gt;Nilarudra Sukta&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The nIlarudra sukta is a part of the atharvaNa veda paippalada saMhitA (14.3). This sukta contains many mantras from the Satarudriyam and the Rudra Suktam of Yajur and Rg Veda, which the reader will identify. But it also contains several new mantras and thus is very interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As always, the sruti seeks to praise srI Lakshmi narasimha only by the name of “Rudra”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OM paśyaṃ tvāvarohantaṃ divitaḥ pṛthivīma ava .&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pravargya beheading</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/pravargya-beheading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/pravargya-beheading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-beheading-of-a-devata-and-the-pravargya-rite&#34;&gt;The Beheading of a Devata and the Pravargya Rite&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the brAhmaNAs, the pravargya ceremony is described. And in the context of that rite, it is also mentioned that some devata got beheaded. The incident is here:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sacred-texts.com/hin/sbr/sbe44/sbe44117.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.sacred-texts.com/hin/sbr/sbe44/sbe44117.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This story is repeated in several other places, but the name of the devata always changes. In the Taittiriya Aranyaka, the devata that lost his head is referred to as “Makha Vaishnava” as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rudra birth</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/rudra-birth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/rudra-birth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;interpretation-of-satapatha-and-kaushitaki-brahmanas-regarding-the-birth-of-rudra&#34;&gt;Interpretation of Satapatha and Kaushitaki Brahmanas regarding the birth of Rudra&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Since interpretation of the brahmaNas is a difficult task, I take refuge in srI vedAnta desikan, known as vedAntAchAryA, kavi tArkika simham and sarva tantra svatantarar, whose srI suktIs are sufficient to make even an ignorant person understand the tattvams, who declared that by mere knowledge of the sarIrAtma bhAva, one would never be defeated in debate, thus establishing the greatness of bhagavad rAmAnujAchAryA.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rudra prashna</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/rudra-prashna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/rudra-prashna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-vaishnava-commentary-on-sri-rudram&#34;&gt;A Vaishnava commentary on Sri Rudram&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(The following material was sent to me by the generous shrIvaiShNava bhAgavata personally by email. It fortifies everything that has been said in the main page of this blog beyond attack.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SrI:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SrimathE rAmAnujAya namaha.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Srimath varavaramunayE namaha.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sri Rudram is a portion of the yajur vedam that consists of 11 anuvAkAs. It is also known as Satarudriyam, Rudraprashnam, RudrOpanishad. At a superficial glance, it appears to be directed to Parvati pati Rudran. Indeed the Satarudriyam Mantras are chanted to pArvati pati in the mahAbhArata, but these sections are of dubious authenticity, as we have explained in &lt;a href=&#34;http://narayanastra.blogspot.com.au/p/blog-page_17.html&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rudra-gItA varAha purANa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/rudra-gItA_varAha-purANa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/rudra-gItA_varAha-purANa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;sri-rudra-gita-varaha-purana&#34;&gt;Sri Rudra Gita (Varaha Purana)&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;pAsho.ayaM pashubhAvastu sa yadA patito bhavet | tadA pAshupataM shAstraM jAyate vedasa&lt;del&gt;nj&lt;/del&gt;nitam ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This pAsha (trap), ie, delusion, is the state or nature of the paShu (anger or attachments) when it becomes wicked. Then the “pAShupata shAstra” ( the shAstra relating to paShupati, the possessor of anger or attachments) becomes suitable to be termed as the Veda.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;~ Rudra Gita (70.43)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The doctrine of paShupati consists of 4 sects – the kApAlikAs, kAlamukhAs, Saiva siddhAnthins and pAShupatas. While there are internal differences between these sects, there are several common aspects – the acceptance of 36 tattvas, non-acceptance of iSvara as the upAdAna kAraNam, Identification of paShupati/rudra/siva as Brahman and the practices such as smearing oneself with ashes, wearing rudrAksha etc. The allied sects are the shAktas, kaumAras, gAnapatyas and tAntrikas, who more or less draw from the same philosophy. The bhAshyam known as “srikaNtha” is a bogus one written by appayya dikshita by plagiarizing the system of srI rAmAnuja (ineffectively and erroneously, we may add) and hence is not considered authentic or part of this system here, having no history of followers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SankarShaNa narasiMha pUjA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/sankarShaNa-narasiMha-pUjA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/sankarShaNa-narasiMha-pUjA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;sankarshana-narasimha-worshipped-by-parvati-pati&#34;&gt;Sankarshana-Narasimha Worshipped by Parvati Pati&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reason why many mistake the Satarudriyam, Rudra Suktam and other such portions of Veda as pertaining to Shiva is because they are unaware that these are names of nArAyaNa. More specifically, all of the names occurring in the Vedas are names of nArAyaNa. For example take the various suktams in the Rg Veda. All the names belong to bhagavAn sriman nArAyaNa only, as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shiva vibhUti yoga</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/shiva-vibhUti-yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/shiva-vibhUti-yoga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;bhagavad-gita-shiva-in-the-vibhuti-yoga-and-vishvarupa-chapters&#34;&gt;Bhagavad Gita: Shiva in the Vibhuti Yoga and Vishvarupa Chapters&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION – THE BHAGAVAD GITA ISSUE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As is well known , ancient shaivas, despite being averse to Vishnu&amp;rsquo;s supremacy in the Vedas, atleast abided by standard norms of debate. They did not consider vedAnta as their domain, and were content with glorifying their deity according to Shaiva Agamas and portions of certain purANas, independent of the vedAntic tradition.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Based on available evidences, we can confidently state that this scenario changed dramatically since the 16th century.  Today&amp;rsquo;s Shaivas, all the way from the scholarly ones like Appayya Dikshita down to the digital-age gurus and &amp;ldquo;experts&amp;rdquo; of miniscule knowledge seen on internet blogs. Having distorted the meaning of Vedic verses such as the Rudram, they have butchered the meaning of mahAbhArata by resorting to interpolated verses denying the supremacy of Vishnu. At the same time, they ignore the innumerable verses that talk about the supremacy of Vishnu, whose authenticity is established by the observation that even Adi Shankara has quoted them. Having done this, they then obscured the narrative of rAmAyaNa, a foremost Srivaishnava shAstra, by claiming rAma worshipped shiva. Finally, they have proceeded to claim that Shiva is praised &amp;ldquo;in all the 18 Puranas&amp;rdquo;, while resorting to nothing but the alleged episodes in tAmasa purAnas that claim shiva to be “matsyEswara”, “kUrmEswara”, “varAhEswara”, “sharabhEswara”, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tripura saMhAra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/tripura-saMhAra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/tripura-saMhAra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;tripura-samhara-as-per-harivamsa-parva&#34;&gt;Tripura Samhara as per Harivamsa Parva&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;T__ime and again, it is being claimed by Saivites that Siva&amp;rsquo;s burning of three cities built by demons (tripura-saMhAra) is a proof of the supremacy of Siva over Brahma and Vishnu. The fact that Vishnu became the head/tip of the arrow is used by Saivites that Vishnu indeed is inferior and therefore not paramAtmA. To any serious reader, these arguments should sound childish and frivolous, since nowhere in the tripura samhAra episode Vishnu is shown as subordinate, as narrated in standard shAstras (Veda, Itihasa, and Sattvika Puranas).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UpaniShad rudra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/upaniShad-rudra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/contra-shaiva/upaniShad-rudra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;rudra-in-the-upanishads-an-analysis&#34;&gt;Rudra in the Upanishads: An analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note 1): This page is a contribution of the Srivaishnava sampradAya follower who represented the side of Vaishnavism with me against the author of the mahapashupatastra blog page.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note 2): There are innumerable verses found in Itihasas, Puranas, and other Smrtis that explain that all the dEvatAs&amp;rsquo; names belong to none other than Vishnu only, because of etymology. Here are a few examples:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pramana #1, from Mahabharata Shanti Parva (credit goes to Sri Krishna Kadiri for pointing out this to us. He is a learned contributor to the dvaita list at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dvaita.info/mailman/listinfo/dvaita-list_dvaita.info&#34;&gt;http://dvaita.info/mailman/listinfo/dvaita-list_dvaita.info&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
