<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;13 Daily Observances on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;13 Daily Observances on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 GETTING UP FROM SLEEP</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/01_GETTING_UP_FROM_SLEEP/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/01_GETTING_UP_FROM_SLEEP/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first thing that one does every day during the early part of the day is the getting up from his bed. He is expected, under ordinary circumstances, to wake up at least half an hour before sunrise and then he is to pronounce the name of God as Hari! Hari! at least six times. Then the person is expected to repeat the ślokas describing the coming of God as Hari and destroying the distress of Gajendra, the chief of the elephants.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 EVACUATION OF THE URINE AND THE FAECES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/02_EVACUATION_OF_THE_URINE_AND_THE_FAECE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/02_EVACUATION_OF_THE_URINE_AND_THE_FAECE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Taking the materials necessary for his bath such as fresh clothes, darbha, rice and sesamum and holding in his hand a bamboo stick and repeating &amp;ldquo;Śrī Kēśavāya namah&amp;rdquo; (I am praying to Kēśava the name of God) he leaves his house. After going a certain distance, he places the materials he takes with him in a place which is clean and determined by him. The place he chooses for taking mud must be one in which no worms are found, not ploughed by a plough, not found mixed with fine &amp;lsquo;alar&amp;rsquo; (soft mud), not mixed up with unholy things, not mingled with soil used by others and free from ant-hills. From such a place he takes enough mud and places this mud close to the place where he is to wash himself. Leaving his sandals he is to slap his palms thrice and then wrap round his head his upper or other cloth. He next winds round his right-ear his sacred thread so that it may not be dangling. His face and mouth are covered with his upper cloth, and then he sits for defaecation. Before sitting for this he should strew the ground with leaves that are dried and those not useful for sacrificial purposes. If the time is twilight or morning he should sit facing north and if the time is night he is expected to sit facing south. While sitting for this he should not speak with any person. He is not expected to sit for defæcation and be seeing temples, rivers, cows, brahmans, fire, sun, moon, air and Ficus religiosa tree. For this purpose he should avoid using the places such as the following:-&amp;ldquo;Flower garden, groves, tulsi gardens, crops, smaśānam (burning ground), alkaline land, hill, ant-hill, pits, unclean spot, sand, shade, ways and paths, water, ploughed land, cowsheds, foot of trees, darbha grown spot, rivers, tanks, sea shore, places where cow dung is stored, yajñabhūmi (place where yajña is performed), [[०५६]]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 WASHING (ŚAUCHAM)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/03_WASHING_shauCham/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/03_WASHING_shauCham/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After defaecation he goes to a place where he has to wash himself taking the mud already secured in his right hand. He divides this mud into four parts and water is to be poured for use by a servant. If, on the other hand, washing is to be done in a pond, mud need not be brought. Rivers and watering places that are near temples or near God should never be used for purposes of washing after passing the faeces. While washing in ponds mud should not be brought from any other place From a place under water, which is as deep as the hand up to the wrists upper limit (a depth of ९ to १० inches), mud must be taken and it should be placed on the ground about ९ to १० inches away from the edge of the water, after sprinkling that space with water Then this mud is used for washing along with water. The left hand is used for washing. It is to be placed between the knees of the two legs and the right hand is kept outside the knees to the right. With his right hand he takes the mud and puts it into his left hand. If passing of the urine and faeces had been done at the same time, cleaning for the faeces has to be done first, and then for urination. If the process of urination and defaecation are at different times, the cleaning has to be done according to the process which has taken place earlier. The cleaning for urination is done by using the mud for cleaning six times and for the passing of the faeces it has to be used twelve or fifteen times. Between one cleaning and another the left hand has to be cleaned five or six times with mud and water. While doing the cleaning for urination, mud about the size of a nellikai (fruit of Phyllanthus emblica) has to be used. For cleaning for defaecation for the first time a handful of mud, for the second and the third time half of this quantity and for the remaining or subsequent washings mud about the size of two nelli fruits should be used.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 SIPPING OF THE WATER (ACHAMANAM)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/04_SIPPING_OF_THE_WATER_ACHAMANAM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/04_SIPPING_OF_THE_WATER_ACHAMANAM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The sipping of the water or achamanam with the proper mentality and mantras is enjoined on all occasions as a purificatory thing. So when the ceremonies or the usual daily observances of any kind are to be begun achamanam has to be performed. For doing achamanam one should sit in a clean place, not squatting, but on feet and knees facing east or north Both the hands are to be kept inside the knees. Touching the hand with the left hand he takes in his right hand as much water as would just be sufficient to drown a seed of black-gram. Then repeating the mantram &amp;ldquo;Om achyutaya namah&amp;rdquo; (I bow to Achyuta) he sips water; this process of sipping water is repeated twice more repeating each time the mantrams &amp;ldquo;Om anantāya namaḥ” (I bow to Ananta)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 CLEANING OF THE TEETH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/05_CLEANING_OF_THE_TEETH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/05_CLEANING_OF_THE_TEETH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cleaning of the teeth is next begun. For this he washes his feet and does achamanam twice. Facing east or north and covering his head with his upper cloth he secures from one of the plants mentioned below a piece of stick six to eight inches long, one and a quarter to one-third of an inch thick, straight, free from nodes, worms and empty hollow portions. The piece he plucks for use must be from one of the following plants :&amp;mdash; Calotropis, banyan, Acacia arabica, Achyranthes, margosa, mango, and others with juice and prickles. The sticks of Bombax, Ficus religiosa, Prosopis spiggera, Areca palm, Butea frondosa, plantain, cotton, darbha grass, cocoanut and nanal grass should not be used. While plucking the stick for use as tooth-brush he is expected to repeat the following mantram:&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;Ayurbalam yaśō varchaḥ prajām paśuvasūni cha . brahma prajñām cha medham cha tvanno dehi Vanaspate.&amp;rdquo; This when translated into English reads thus &amp;ldquo;Oh! king of the wood give us life, strength, fame, brilliance, children, cows, riches or property, knowledge of God, intelligence or wisdom.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 BATHING OR SNANAM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/06_BATHING_OR_SNANAM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/06_BATHING_OR_SNANAM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One who intends bathing in a tank or river should go to a place where God is usually brought or where Bhagavatās bathe. Selecting such a place he should clean with water the place he intends sitting, wash his legs and hands and then sit on this space facing east or north. While sitting he should wear on his ring-finger of the righthand the pavitra, usually of darbha grass twisted, and do prānāyāmam three times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 PUTTING ON THE URDHVA PUNDRAM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/07_PUTTING_ON_THE_URDHVA_PUNDRAM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/07_PUTTING_ON_THE_URDHVA_PUNDRAM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The person who is about to put on the ūrdhvapundram (marks made on the forehead and parts of his body with a kind of white clay and turmeric powder) takes water in a coconut-shell or &amp;ldquo;Tirthahari.&amp;rdquo; From this coconut-shell he takes a little water and pours it into his left hand by means of an uddharani (a spoon) made of gold, silver or wood.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With this water he cleans his left hand repeating the astramantra &amp;ldquo;Vīryāya astrāyaphat.&amp;rdquo; Then repeating the pranavam he places the tiruman (white clay or mud) in his left hand in his palm Then repeating the mantram &amp;ldquo;Gandhadvaram durādharsham nityapushṭām karishinim . Isvarim sarva bhūtanām tvamiha upahvaye śriyam&amp;rdquo; (this when translated runs thus &amp;ldquo;I invite here the deity of Earth who is resorted to by all, who is perceived by smell, who is not overcome by enemies, who is always full of plenty, who is full of cattle (cows, buffaloes, etc.,) and who creates and directs all the objects of creation] the tiruman is rubbed in and dissolved in a small quantity of water. Then with astra mantra ashṭadigbandhanam is done. (The eight directions are closed by the repetition of the mantras). Then by repeating the pranava the tiruman is dissolved in water by rubbing it in the palm, the mūla mantra is repeated over it, then Nrsimha bijakshara is written on it and it is then dissolved and mixed well by using the fore finger. Then over this he repeats the mantra &amp;ldquo;Vishnor-nukam Viryani pravōcham yaḥ pārthivani vimamē rajāmsi yöaskabhāyaduttaram sadhastam vichakramāṇastrēdhōrugāyah.&amp;rdquo; This when translated runs thus &amp;ldquo;I shall fully describe the powerful deeds of Vishnu who is extolled by great men, who created the three lights, namely, fire, lightning and the sun on Earth, the intermediate region and the sky or heaven and who created the very extensions, the antariksha which supports the three worlds by walking over them with a stride in each (or who has firmly established heaven which is above all worlds and where yögis dwell).&amp;rdquo; He also repeats the dwadaśākshara mantra. After this he repeats the following mantra &amp;ldquo;Vishnoraratamasi vishnoh prshthamasi Vishnoh snaptrestho vishnōssyūrasi Vishnor dhruvamasi Vaishnavamasi visnavētvā uddhrtasi varāhēṇa krshněna śata bāhunal bhūmir dhēnūr dharanibhūtadhārini . mrttikē hanamēpāpam yan mayā dushkṛtam kṛtam . tvayā hatēna pāpēna jīvāmi śaradaśśatam . mrttikë dehī më pushtim tvayi sarvam pratishthitam.&amp;rdquo; This when translated runs thus &amp;ldquo;You are the forehead of Vishnu, you are the back of Vishnu, you are the joints of the lips of Vishnu, you are one that connects us with Vishnu, you are as firm as Vishnu, you have Vishnu as the presiding deity, and you are Vishnu himself. Oh Earth! you have been brought back by the thousand hands of Vishnu in his boar incarnation; you are like the milch cow always giving us what we require; you are the bearer of truth and support all objects of life Oh Earth! destroy my sins and destroy all bad acts that I have done. Having been relieved of my sins let me live one hundred years. Oh Earth! give me comfort, for all the objects capable of giving comfort are stationed in you.&amp;rdquo; He then takes with the index finger a small quantity of tiruman dissolved in the hand and smears it over the head repeating the pranavam at the same time. With the fourth finger pavitra finger) he makes marks of tiruman on the face and other parts of the body in [[०६२]]&#xA;[[५७]]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 OFFERINGS OF WATER AND RICE TO DEVARSHIS AND FOREFATHERS (DĒVARSHI PITR TARPANAM)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/08_OFFERINGS_OF_WATER_AND_RICE_TO_DEVARS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/08_OFFERINGS_OF_WATER_AND_RICE_TO_DEVARS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The performer cleans his hand and feet with water and then does achamanam and sankalpam to perform the Devarshi and Pitr tarpanams as follows:&amp;ndash;&amp;quot; Śrīman Narayana pprītyartham snānāngam dēvarshi pitr tarpaṇam karishye.&amp;quot; He performs the tarpanam believing that devatas, rshis and pitrs have in them the amsam of God. That is to say he should believe that the spirit of God is in all these.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then repeating the following mantras he does tarpaṇam, l.e., leaves water mixed with rice and sesamum in his hands as described below :&amp;mdash; &amp;ldquo;Brahmādayō yēdēvāstān dēvāmstarpayami . sarvān dēvāmstarpayāmi . sarvadēva ganāmstarpayāmi . sarva dēva patnīstarpayāmi . sarvadeva ganapatnīstarpayami.&amp;rdquo; This in English means &amp;ldquo;I please all Devas from Brahma downwards by the libations of water. I please all Devas by these libations of water. I please all troops of Devas by these libations of water. I please all the wives of the Devas by these libations of water.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 MORNING PRAYERS (MORNING SANDHYAVANDANAM)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/09_MORNING_PRAYERS_MORNING_SANDHYAVANDAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/09_MORNING_PRAYERS_MORNING_SANDHYAVANDAN/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Sandhyāvandanam is performed by the very orthodox Brahmans as detailed in Ahannikams (books describing the various rites usually observed by the orthodox Sri Vaishnava Brahmans). Sri Vaishnava Brahmans who are not orthodox perform this Sandhyavandanam using only some of the mantras, leaving out many as of secondary importance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ceremony of Sandhyāvandanam is begun by doing achamanam twice. After doing the achamanam the performer repeats Srībhagavadājñyayā śrīmannārāyaṇa prītyartham prātassandhyamupasishye.&amp;quot; This when translated runs thus :- &amp;ldquo;I am now engaged in the prayer during the morning of twilight under the orders of the divine Lord for propitiating the Lord Narayana who is associated with Lakshmi &amp;quot;&#xA;After repeating the above mantra the performer repeats &amp;ldquo;Kritanchakarishyāmi.&amp;rdquo; Then he repeats &amp;ldquo;Pratassandhyāvandanākhyēna bhagavatkarmana bhagavantam archayishyāmi.&amp;rdquo; This when translated runs as follows:-&amp;ldquo;I worship the divine Lord by this divine action known by the name of prayer during the morning twilight.&amp;rdquo; Next he repeats the mantra beginning with &amp;ldquo;Bhagavato balēna&amp;rdquo; and repeats the bala mantra to its end which is &amp;ldquo;Bhagavato Vasudevasya.&amp;rdquo; This when translated runs thus:- &amp;ldquo;By the strength given by God of the Divine Lord Vasudeva. He then begins by repeating &amp;ldquo;Bhagavānēva&amp;rdquo; and does satvikatyāga by repeating &amp;ldquo;Prātassandhyōpasanakhyam karmasvasmai svaprītyae svayamēva kārayati.&amp;rdquo; This when translated runs thus :-&amp;ldquo;God himself makes me do the action of morning prayer for his own gratification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 REPETITION OF THE ASHTĀKSHARAM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/10_REPETITION_OF_THE_ashtAksharam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/10_REPETITION_OF_THE_ashtAksharam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This japam is performed only by those who have been initiated fully and by those who have passed through the ceremony of prapatti (See Pl I-A).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The japa is begun by repeating the taniyans (stanzas in praise) of his own Āchārya who initiated the performer and taught the vākya gurupāramparā, Ślōka [[०७४]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[६९]]&#xA;guruparamparā, mantra, mantrartha, and then he should repeat the mūla mantra twenty-five times and do prāṇāyāmam. Then he performs the sankalpam repeating the following mantra :- &amp;quot; Śri bhagavadajňaya Srimannārāyanaprītyartham prātāśsandhyāyām ashṭōttara śatakritvah (or daśakritvah) ashtaksharamahamantrajapam karishye.&amp;quot; He does nyāsam repeating as follows:-&amp;quot; Asya śrīmad ashtakshara maha mantrasya badarikāśramavasinārāyaṇa rshih dēvī gāyatrīchandah . paramātmā śrīmannārāyanō dēvata,&amp;quot; and then contemplates about Narayana. The translation in English of the above is &amp;ldquo;Narayana rshi is the seer of the divine, eight syllabled mantra, the metre is the divine gayatri, the presiding deity is Narayana associated with Lakshmi and the Lord of all.&amp;rdquo; The contemplation of Narayana is done by repeating the following:&amp;mdash; &amp;ldquo;Aum bijam, āyaśaktiḥ, mām kīlakam, hrim kavacham, buddhistatvam, udattādisvaraḥ . Śrī Vaikuntham Kshetram jīvaparamātmanōḥ svasvamibhāvassambandhah . śrimannārāyanaprītyarthe japë viniyogaḥ &amp;ldquo;॥.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 1 ABHIGAMANA ĀRĀDHANAM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/11_1_ABHIGAMANA_ArAdhanam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/11_1_ABHIGAMANA_ArAdhanam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The worshipper, before entering the temple, wears flowers, sandal and clothing, cleanses his mouth by means of water after chewing betel-leaf and nuts and cleans his hands and feet. As soon as he enters the temple, he stands at a distance and prostrates before God. Getting up and with the permission of the two dvārapālakās he enters the temple precincts to near God and while doing so he repeats the following :—“ Kausalya suprajā Rāma Pūrvāsandhya pravartate ūttishtha naraśārdūla kartavyam daivāmahnikam Vīra saumya vibuddhyāswa kausalyānandavardhana jagaddhi sarvam svapititvayi supte parantapa॥ Yāminyapaiti yadunātha vimuncha nidrām unmeśhaṁṛcchati tavōnmīshitē na viśvam . jātasvyaṁ khalu jagaddhitamēva kartum dharmapravartana dhiyā dharaṇītalesmin.&amp;quot; This when translated runs thus:&amp;mdash;-&amp;ldquo;Oh Rama! Kausalya is very fortunate in having a good son. The morning twilight is dawning in the East.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 2 UPĀDĀNAM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/11_2_upAdAnam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/11_2_upAdAnam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the second yamam he does sankalpa repeating &amp;ldquo;Krtancha upādānena archayishyāmi.&amp;rdquo; Then he repeats the Balamantra &amp;ldquo;Bhagavānēva upādānākhyam kārayati&amp;rdquo; and does satvikatyagam. The person who wants to perform this part of the ceremony is expected to secure flowers, fruits, and other things needed for the worship of God. Only flowers that are clean and found on plants growing in clean situations and those accepted as fit by older Acharyas are to be secured for use. Flowers having good smell, and are beautiful to look at, ghee, milk and curds are to be secured for use. They are to be cleaned properly and kept for use Flowers that are grown by the activity of a person are superior. Those flowers that are secured from plants growing in a wild state are not very good and they have only a medium value. Those purchased in the bazaar are about the worst in value. Flowers secured stealthily or by begging are very bad. Flowers white in colour belong to the class satvika. Red flowers are put under rājasa and blue and black belong to the tamasa class. One should avoid flowers growing on plants found in unclean places; those flowers that are faded, those that are not full, unripe buds, old flowers are also to be avoided; flowers used by any body, flowers smelt, flowers touched by unclean animals, flowers with worms in them are also to be avoided. Flowers of oleander should never be used in houses for God&amp;rsquo;s archana.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11.0 AUPĀSANAM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/11_0_aupAsanam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/11_0_aupAsanam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;upload-download&#34;&gt;Upload/ download&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The worshipper approaches the fire which he used the previous day, after washing his legs and doing two achamanams. For use he takes fire from this by using darbha or samit and mixes it with fire in the place where he intends doing the ceremony and he repeats the following mantra while burning the samit or the darbha in the fire:-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Upavaroha jātavedah punastvam dēvēbhyo havyam vahanaḥ prajānān āyuḥ prajāmrayimasmāsudhehi ajasrodidihino durone&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 MADHYAHNIKA SNĀNAM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/12_MADHYAHNIKA_snAnam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/12_MADHYAHNIKA_snAnam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this snānam also some mantras are repeated as for bathing in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just before the bath he repeats the following:-&amp;quot; Avāhayāmi tvām devi snānārthamiha sundari ehigange namastubhyam sarvatirthasamanvite.&amp;quot; This when translated runs thus:-&amp;quot; Oh beautiful Goddess! I invite you here for my bathing Oh Ganga! salutation to thee, who possess all the sacred waters of the world.&amp;quot; The usual sankalpa, bala mantra and satvikatyāga mantra are repeated before the above mantra. Repeating the above āvāhana mantra he takes water in both his hands and invokes Ganga to come over there. Then arghyam is given repeating &amp;ldquo;Vishnu vāmā padāngushtha nakhaśrōtō vinisrute . tadbhakti vighna rūpāt tvam gange mam mochayainasah ॥.&amp;rdquo; This in English runs thus:-&amp;quot; Oh Ganga that came out from the nail of the left great toe of Vishnu! Please release me from the sins which stand as obstacles to his devotions.&amp;quot; He then bathes for the midday as for the morning and dresses himself as usual after the bath.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 MADHYAHNIKAM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/13_MADHYAHNIKAM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/13_MADHYAHNIKAM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He does achamanams as for the morning Sandhya Vandanam, but in the Sankalpam instead of &amp;ldquo;Pratassandhyām&amp;rdquo; he has to say &amp;ldquo;Madhyāhnika sandhyām.&amp;rdquo; After [[०९१]]&#xA;[[८६]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;pranayamam he repeats the following:&amp;ndash;&amp;quot; Apahpunantvityanuvākasya aparshiḥ anushtup cchandah brahmanaspatirdēvata . apām praśanë viniyogah.&amp;quot; Translation:&amp;ndash;For the anuvāka &amp;ldquo;Apahpunantu&amp;rdquo; Āpas are Rshi, and Anushtup is chandas and the Devata is Brahmanaspati.&amp;quot; Then taking water in the right hand he repeats &amp;ldquo;Apahpunantu prithivim prithivi pūtā punātumām, punantu brahmanaspatih brahmaputa punatumam, yaducchishtam abhojyam yadva duscharitam mama . sarvam punantumāmāpah astamcha pratigraham svāhā&amp;rdquo; and drinks it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 ARĀDHANAM OR WORSHIP</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/14_arAdhanam_OR_WORSHIP/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/14_arAdhanam_OR_WORSHIP/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The person who intends to do worship to God, at first attends to his personal cleanliness. He cleans his feet and hands and then selects a suitable place for him.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This place is cleaned by repeating the sōshaṇa, dahana and plavana mantras. Sitting on the place thus selected he meditates on the parampara of his gurus and God. He is to think that the end and aim of his is only to attain God&amp;rsquo;s presence and the only way to attain Him is His grace. He should also think that God is the only person who can remove unpleasant things and think of the svarupa, rūpa, character and vibhūtis of God. He should try to approach God&amp;rsquo;s feet by repeating the stotra ślokās beginning with &amp;ldquo;Akhilahēyapratyanika.&amp;rdquo; After attaining the feet of God and with mind strengthened by his favour, he should think of God only as one dear to him and as one whom he is always thinking as being before him. Then with the grace arising from such a devotion he is to begin the worship of God. Repeating &amp;ldquo;Bhagavānēva upakramatē&amp;rdquo; he does nyasam with panchopanishad mantras in samhāra order and then does one pranayamam. With his right hand he touches his navel repeating the mūla mantra and afterwards says &amp;ldquo;Mantrōdbhūta chanda vāyvāpyayita nābhi dēśastha vayunā śarīramantarbahischa tatvakramena śōshayāmi.&amp;rdquo; This in English is as follows:&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;I dry up the body both internally and externally in the order of tatvas by which it is constituted, by the wind situated in the navel being spread up by the chandra vayu proceeding from the mantra uttered.&amp;rdquo; After repeating the above mantra he thinks that his whole body has been dried up (soshanam).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 VAISVADĒVAM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/15_vaisvadvam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/15_vaisvadvam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This ceremony is usually done only by the very orthodox people. Persons who do this ceremony make use of the food taken by them from the food offered to God during the aradhanam of God and towards the end of the ceremony. The performer cleans his feet, does two achamanams and a pranayamam. Then he begins this ceremony of Vaisvadēvam by repeating &amp;ldquo;Śri bhagavadājñayā śrimannārāyanaprītyartham pratar Vārśvadēvam karishye. He then repeats &amp;ldquo;Krtancha karishyāmi&amp;rdquo; and says &amp;ldquo;Prātar vaiśvadēvēna bhagavatkarmanā bhagavantam Vasudevamarchayishyāmi.&amp;rdquo; After this he continues to repeat &amp;ldquo;Bhagavato balena&amp;rdquo; and then does satvikatyāgam by repeating &amp;ldquo;Bhagavānēva prātar vaisvadēvākhyam karma kārayati&amp;rdquo; He makes use of agni in the pit which is either aupasanāgni or agni which was used for cooking the food. After putting the fire in the pit he draws lines and does agni pratishthai and paristaranam as is usually done for aupasanam. His wife brings food cooked by her and set apart for vaiśvadēvam and gives it to him saying &amp;ldquo;Bhūtam.&amp;rdquo; Saying &amp;ldquo;Tatsubhūtam Viradannam tanmā kshāyi&amp;rdquo; he takes the food and shows it to fire. The above when translated runs thus:-&amp;ldquo;The food is well completed and well embellished. Therefore it will not perish.&amp;rdquo; He takes the food and shows it to fire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 PANCHAMAHĀYAJÑAM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/16_panChamahAyajnam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/16_panChamahAyajnam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Immediately after Vaiśvadeva the person performs this ceremonial, Panchamahayajñam. He begins this ceremonial by doing &amp;ldquo;śrotrachamanam&amp;rdquo; and prāṇāyāmam in the usual way. Then he does sankalpam repeating &amp;ldquo;Śrībhagavadājñaya dēva yajñēna yakshye.&amp;rdquo; Taking water he washes his left hand repeating &amp;ldquo;Vidyudasi&amp;rdquo; and then repeating &amp;ldquo;Aditēnu manyasva prasūva &amp;quot; does pariṣechanaṁ to agni (i.e., take round water) and puts in fire a samit or darbha. After this he takes the food from the part in the east which is marked off as the northern part, and repeating “Om dēvēbhyasvaha&amp;rdquo; puts in the fire, and then repeats &amp;quot; Devebhya idam na mama&amp;quot; and places in the fire a darbha. Then once again he pours water round the fire repeating during the process &amp;ldquo;Om aditēnu prāsāvih&amp;rdquo; and smears the hands repeating &amp;ldquo;Vrshtirasi.&amp;rdquo; The meanings of the above Sanskrit passages are given here seriatim :&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;This food is [[०९८]]&#xA;[[९३]]&#xA;offered to the devas. This offering belongs to the Devas and it is not mine or it does not belong to me. You are the cause of cutting.&amp;rdquo; Again he does śrotrachamanam and wearing the yajñopavita with the left hand through it and the string on the right shoulder (i.e., prāchinviti) repeats &amp;ldquo;Śrībhagavadajñayā . . pitṛ yajñēna yakshye&amp;rdquo; doing sankalpam. He smears the hands repeating &amp;ldquo;Vidyudasi.&amp;rdquo; The above Sanskrit when rendered into English run thus:-&amp;ldquo;I make the sacrifice by pitṛ yajña. You are the cause of separation&amp;rdquo;. He pours water and smears the earth to the south of the fire pit and takes a small quantity of food from the cup again and repeating &amp;lsquo;Om pitṛbhyassvadha&amp;quot; places his hand on the ground Then repeating &amp;ldquo;Pitṛbhya idam na mama&amp;rdquo; he pours water in the apradakshiṇa way round the fire and cleans his hands by wiping while repeating &amp;ldquo;Vṛṣṭirasi.&amp;rdquo; The meaning of the Sanskrit in the above runs thus: &amp;ldquo;I offer this ball of rice to Pitṛs. This offering belongs to Pitṛs and it does not belong to me. You are the cause of cutting.&amp;rdquo; Putting the yajñopavīta in the right way he does śrotrachamanam and prāṇāyāmam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 BHOJANAM (TAKING ONE&#39;S FOOD)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/17_BHOJANAM_TAKING_ONES_FOOD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/17_BHOJANAM_TAKING_ONES_FOOD/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The person proposing to eat, washes his feet, does achamanam twice and cleans a space in his front with water mixing with it a little of cow&amp;rsquo;s urine. On the spot thus [[०९९]]&#xA;[[९४]]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;cleaned he places a plantain leaf after cleaning it well with water. A vessel filled with water is placed on his right side and he sits in front of the leaf. He should not sit at any time facing west but he may choose anyone of the remaining three. In his right hand he is expected to have a golden pavitram (a form of ring) on his ring finger and if he does not possess one he should make a pavitra out of darbha and put it on that finger.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 SVADHYAYAM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/18_SVADHYAYAM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/18_SVADHYAYAM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[[९७]]&#xA;In the fourth yāma he does sankalpam as follows:-&amp;quot; Krtancha svādhyāyēna archayishyāmi.&amp;quot; Then he repeats the bala mantra &amp;ldquo;Bhagavānēva svādhyāyākhyam karma karayati&amp;rdquo; and does satvikatyāgam. He then goes on reading about upanishads, the meanings and applications of the meanings of mūlamantra, studying Śrībhashya, reading of grandhas about God and his doings, Śrīmad Ramayana, Bhagavadgītā, and Bharata, and doing tatva nirnayas with Brahmacharis and disciples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 SANDHYAVANDANAM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/19_SANDHYAVANDANAM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/19_SANDHYAVANDANAM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Towards evening one should change his cloths by wearing fresh ones and do the evening sandhyavandanam. The performer is expected to clean his hands and feet and do prāṇāyāmam. Then he does sankalpam repeating &amp;ldquo;Śrībhagavadajñaya Śrīman Nārāyaṇaprītyartham sayam sandhyamupāsishyē&amp;rdquo;. Prokshana, etc., are done as in the morning sandhyāvandanam. He does nyasam by repeating &amp;ldquo;Agniśchētyanuvākasya Suryarshiḥ . devīgayatricchandah . agnirdevatā.&amp;rdquo; Then he takes water in his right hand as if for achamana and says &amp;ldquo;Apām prāśaně viniyogah&amp;rdquo; He then says the mantra &amp;ldquo;Agni- ścha māmanyuaścha manyupatayaścha manyukrtebhyaḥ . pāpēbhyorakshantam yadahnā papama kārsham . manasā vāchā hastābhyām padbhyā mudarēna śiśnā . ahastadavalumpatu yat kincha duritam mayi idamaham mamamrtayōnau . satyējyotishi juhō- mi svāhā &amp;quot; and drinks the water in his hand. (Same meaning as the mantra Sūryascha but some words are changed and they are &amp;ldquo;agniścha&amp;rdquo; = fire; &amp;ldquo;ahna&amp;rdquo;= day time (in the day time); aha=day time, &amp;ldquo;satye&amp;rdquo;== in the form of satyam. The arghya is done facing the west now. Other things are done as in the morning sandhyā.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 YOGA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/20_YOGA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/kriyA/shrI-vaishNava-brAhmaNas_rangAchAri/13_Daily_Observances/20_YOGA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He cleans his legs and hands and does the usual achamanam. Sitting in a clean spot facing east he does three pranayamams. Then he does sankalpam repeating &amp;ldquo;Krtancha Yogēna Archayishyāmi.&amp;rdquo; Next he does satvikatyāga repeating &amp;ldquo;Bhagavānēva.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;yogākhyam kārayati.&amp;rdquo; He repeats after this &amp;ldquo;Amalanādipiran, Śrī Vaikuntha gadya, Bhagavaddhyāna Sopānam, etc. and contenplates on God&amp;rsquo;s greatness and his good doings. As soon as he feels sleepy he lies down believing that he is placing his head at the feet of God. If he wakes from sleep till he sleeps again he contemplates on God. Sleep is to be considered as rest to enable one to be able to do Bhagavad āradhana, etc., during the day as usual.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
