<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;En on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;En on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RangAchAri</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/en/rangAchAri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/en/rangAchAri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;सत्यमेव जयते&#xA;संस्कृति मंत्रालय&#xA;● भारत सरकार&#xA;I BHASHYAM&#xA;Vol. I-Chap. I&#xA;LISA&#xA;2&#xA;SL&#xA;ASTRY OF CULT&#xA;सत्यमेव जयते&#xA;VERNMENT OF INDIA.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;भारत सरकार&#xA;A5000 173&#xA;SL&#xA;SRI BHASHYAM&#xA;संस्कृति मंत्रालय&#xA;TRANSLATED INTO ENGLISH&#xA;70&#xA;BY&#xA;&amp;lsquo;DIWAN BAHADUR V. K. RAMANUJACHARI&#xA;SECRETAR&#xA;NO 7159&#xA;LIBRA&#xA;16 APR 1934&#xA;84&#xA;FOVLE&amp;amp;LLS OF ALIA&#xA;Vol. 1-Chap. I&#xA;PUBLISHED BY THE AUTHOR&#xA;AT KUMBAKONAM&#xA;30&#xA;DE CULTURE&#xA;MINISTRY&#xA;GOVERNMENT&#xA;F INDIA&#xA;सत्यमेव जयते&#xA;● भारत सरकार&#xA;संस्कृति मंत्रालय&#xA;MAYHEAD 192&#xA;GL&#xA;NONE OTH&#xA;181.4 Ram N308&#xA;COPYRIGHT&#xA;The right of Translation and reproction is reserved&#xA;1679&#xA;MINISTRY OF CULTU&#xA;संस्कृति मंत्रालय&#xA;सत्यमेव जयते&#xA;VERNMENT OF INDIA.&#xA;भारत सरका&#xA;SL&#xA;FOREWORD&#xA;IN placing an English translation of the Sri Bhashyam before the public a few words of explanation are needed. The view is held by western sanskrit scholars that the Veda consists of portions written by different persons at different times, and that therefore conflicts of opinion must necessarily follow. This is not the view held by such eminent rishis as Jaimini and Badarayana, and by a host of other rishis, who have&#xA;wr&#xA;kalpa sutras, smritis, itihasas and puranas. They were of opinion that the veda was not written by any one; that it is one work; and that therefore no text of the veda should conflict with any other text. It is in this view that Badarayana wrote his sutras, and that Sri Ramanuja wrote his Sri Bhashyam.&#xA;2. Readers of the upanishads will observe that reference is made in them to three tatvas or substances- matter, the jivas and Isvara. Certain texts state that they are different from one another in their svarupas (substance) and in their natures. Matter serves the jivas by undergoing transformations, and appearing as objects of enjoyment, as bodies in which the jivas dwell, and as senses and organs of action, which they use as instruments of enjoyment. The jivas utilise the&#xA;OF CULTURE&#xA;MINISTRY OF&#xA;संस्कृति मंत्रालय&#xA;GOVERNMENT&#xA;सत्यमेव जयते&#xA;● भारत सरकार&#xA;vi&#xA;4&#xA;GL&#xA;bodies, the senses and the organs of action, and ex- perience pleasure or pain from material products. And Işvara gives the jivas the fruits of their past karmas, and makes matter undergo such transformations as are needed for this purpose. Certain other texts of the veda state that Isvara is identical with the universe, consis- ting of the jivas and material products. How is this apparent conflict to be explained? The veda itself replies by stating that all objects are the bodies of Isvara, and that He is their atma. It is usual in the world to speak of the body and atma as being identical, as in the statement Devadatta is stout&amp;rsquo;. The term devadatta&amp;rsquo; denotes a jiva, and the term &amp;lsquo;stout&amp;rsquo; refers to his body. The jiva, being atomic in size, cannot be said to be stout or lean. Similarly, the veda speaks of Isvara and the universe as one, as they bear to each other the relation of atma and body. In this expla- nation all vedic texts are accepted as of equal validity; and there is no need to regard one set of texts as nullified by another set. Accepting this explanation, which was that suggested by the rishi (seer) Kaṣakritsna (see sutra I-4-22), the sutras are interpreted in the Sri Bhashyam.&#xA;6&#xA;3. Other commentators of the sutras accept the texts affirming identity as stating the truth, and explain the texts stating the tatvas to be different from one another. Sankara is of opinion that Brahma alone exists; nothing else; and that the appearance of the universe, consisting of numberless persons that perceive, and of numberless objects that are perceived, is illusion;MINISTRY OF CULTUR&#xA;GOVERNMENT&#xA;सत्यमेव जयते&#xA;संस्कृति मंत्रालय भारत सरकार&#xA;vii&#xA;SL&#xA;an at this is brought about by an unreal avidya resting on Brahma. Bhaskara explains that Brahma Himself becomes jivas by contact with upadhis, i.e., atomic substances known as antaḥ karana (mind). The places in Brahma not so contacted is Brahma. Yadava Prakaṣa states that the same substance, which he calls sat, appears in three forms-as Isvara, as jivas and as matter. The theories of these commentators are ex- amined in Sri Bhashyam in the sub-sections noted on the margin and shown to be untenable. This examination has been taken out and translated as a separate work with the title &amp;ldquo;The Three&#xA;Chapter 1, sec-&#xA;tion 1, sub-sections 1 and 4; and chap-&#xA;sub-section 6.&#xA;ter II, section 1, Tatvas&amp;rdquo;. The Sri Bhashyam is intended to be a practical guide to enable the jivas to get rid of their samsara (cycle of births and deaths), and to attain bliss in no way alloyed with pain and enduring for ever. It shows for this purpose that there is a Being known as highest Atma, who is free from every imper- fection, and who is the seat of numberless, infinitely high, noble qualities; that the way to reach Him is by continuous, vivid and loving meditation on Him; and that when this meditation is established, all the jiva&amp;rsquo;s past karmas are destroyed; that such karmas, as are not consciously done, will not touch him; that with the grace of the highest Atma, who abides in his heart as his ātmā, he will rise from his body through a blood- vessel that goes to the top of his head; that he will travel along a path known as devayana, and that on reaching the highest Atma in a place beyond this world of matter, he will attain his own nature, and thereaft&#xA;OF CULTUR&#xA;कृति मंत्रालय&#xA;सत्यमेव जयते&#xA;• भत&#xA;ERNMENT OF INDIA.&#xA;सरकार&#xA;viii&#xA;GL&#xA;enjoy the highest Atma and His noble qualities, and that he will never return to samsara. Most readers will be satisfied with the Sri Bhashyam without the contro- versial portion. It has therefore been taken out. Those, that wish to know how the other theories are unsound, may read &amp;ldquo;The Three Tatvas&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;4. Certain followers of Sankara have criticised the interpretations of the sutras given in the Sri Bhashyam. They have been answered by mahamahopadhyaya Kapis- talam Desikacharyar, and Mr. A. V. Gopalacharyar, M.A., B.L. A third work is ready, having been written by Agnihotram Tata Desika Tatacharyar of Kumba- konam. All these are in Sanskrit. If there is a general desire in the English-knowing public to know what they say, a brief resume of the contents of these works will be prepared with the consent of their authors.&#xA;5. With the omission referred to in para 3, the translation keeps close to the original. I have availed myself of some latitude in order to make the translation intelligible. Portions of the commentary known as sruta prakasika have been incorporated in the text, where the text would be unintelligible without the commentary, Portions of the text, which treat of small matters, or quote vedic and smriti texts, which are well- known, have been put in the form of foot-notes. Not one grain of matter has been omitted, and the transla- tion faithfully reproduces the original. The vedic texts considered in the various sub-sections have been sepa- ately translated, with an abstract of the contexts in hich they occur, and with copious notes from the&#xA;RY OF&#xA;सायमेव जयते&#xA;ERNMENT OF INDIA.&#xA;संस्कृति मंत्र भारत सरकार&#xA;ix&#xA;upanishad bhashya of Ranga Ramanuja.&#xA;6&#xA;SL&#xA;Sanskrit&#xA;terms have been translated within brackets, wherever they occur; nevertheless a glossary of the terms has been appended at the end. It is difficult to prepare an index; but the table of contents, which will be found at the beginning, will serve the purpose of an index to some extent.&#xA;6. No pains have been spared to make the trans- lation intelligible by itself. It was prepared several years ago; and it has undergone revision twice, not to mention minor alterations made in passing the proofs. My thanks are due to (1) Mr. K. Sadagopa Aiyangar, retired Salt Inspector, Kumbakonam for examining the translation with the original, and for correcting the proof sheets; (2) to Sinnamu Srinivasa Patracharyar of the same place for valuable help in the elucidation of difficult points; (3) to Mr. A. K. Sitarama Sastriar, Superintendent, Vasanta Press, Adyar, Madras, for careful printing and neat execution; and lastly (4) to my Guru (Srimad Andavan of Srirangam), who gave me permission to print the translation, and whose blessing has brought the printing to a successful end.&#xA;7. An explanation of abbreviations used in the work is subjoined.&#xA;Kumbakonam&#xA;1 November, 1930&#xA;V. K. RAMANUJACHARI&#xA;B&#xA;MINISTRY OF CULT&#xA;OF CULTURE&#xA;RNMENT OF INDIA&#xA;GOVERNMENT&#xA;सत्यमेव जयते&#xA;संस्कृति मंत्रालय&#xA;भारत सरकार&#xA;.&#xA;SL&#xA;LIST OF ABBREVIATIONS&#xA;Adhikarana Sāravali of Sri Desika.&#xA;Adhi.&#xA;Aita.&#xA;Aitareya upanishad.&#xA;Ana.&#xA;Anandavalli.&#xA;Brihad. Brihad Aranyaka upanishad.&#xA;Bhāva. Bhavaprakaṣika of Ranga Ramanuja.&#xA;Bhrigu. Bhriguvalli.&#xA;Chando. Chandogya upanishad.&#xA;Isa.&#xA;Katha.&#xA;Iṣavasya upanishad.&#xA;Kathavalli.&#xA;Kaushi. Kaushitaki brahmana.&#xA;Munda. Mundaka upanishad.&#xA;Nārāyaṇam of Taittiriya upanishad.&#xA;Nara.&#xA;Puru.&#xA;Purusha sukta.&#xA;Sveta.&#xA;Svetasvatara upanishad.&#xA;Suba.&#xA;Subala upanishad.&#xA;Taitti.&#xA;Taittiriya upanishad.&#xA;OF CUT&#xA;GOVERNMENT&#xA;सत्यमेव जयते&#xA;• संस्कृति मंत्रालय&#xA;T OF INDIA&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
