<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;नारायणास्त्र-वृन्दम् on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;नारायणास्त्र-वृन्दम् on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BANAsura charitam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/bANAsura-charitam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/bANAsura-charitam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;banasura-charitra-inner-meanings&#34;&gt;Banasura Charitra: Inner Meanings&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many leelAs of sriman nArAyaNa which highlight several different kalyAna gunams and contain important tattvArthams. These include Draupadi VastrApaharanam, Gajendra Moksham, KAkAsura VriddhAntham, PAndava Dhoothan, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One such incident is BAnAsura Charithram. This episode highlights the veeryam of sriman nArAyaNa in addition to his kalyAna gunams of swAmithvam (ruler of all), parathvam (the supreme), soulabhyam (ease of accessibility) and rakshagatvam (protection).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this war, there is no devas = good and asuras = evil. Everyone, devas and asuras who fought against bhagavAn were overcome by the ajnAna of prakrti and hence, in tamo gunA.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BhAgavata validity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/bhAgavata-validity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/bhAgavata-validity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;validity-of-srimad-bhagavatam&#34;&gt;Validity of Srimad Bhagavatam&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several readers have queried us regarding a particular article written on the Bhagavata Purana, called “Bhagavata Purana Samiksha” - &lt;a href=&#34;https://kamakotimandali.com/~kamakoti/misc/mahapurana.html&#34;&gt;https://kamakotimandali.com/~kamakoti/misc/mahapurana.html&lt;/a&gt;. Here, the author seeks to establish that the Devi Bhagavatam is the “true Bhagavatam” and that Shrimad Bhagavatam is an Upapurana. It should be noted that Vedantins of all backgrounds have only admitted that the Shrimad Bhagavatam is the authentic text – any question of authenticity is decided by the acceptance among ancient Vedantins. To that effect, we have the following proofs:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BhIShma stava</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/bhIShma-stava/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/bhIShma-stava/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;sri-bhishma-stavam&#34;&gt;Sri Bhishma Stavam&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dear all,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While digging up material for my study of the Ishvara gIta in the kUrma purANa, I came upon this. In the Santi parva of theMahabhArata, there is a touching stOtra by shrI bhIshmAchArya. He recognizes the Lord nArAyaNa as the Supreme Being, and as krishNa who is standing before him.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is an incredibly touching stOtra of one who was such a great jnAni, yet reduced to the bed of arrows, who has realized the supreme tattvas. Also touching is fact that the Lord to whom it has been addressed to, is full of auspicious attributes, who “a-mAni” as per the sahasranAma (never proud), who stood respectfully at the side of bhIshma as though he was an inferior, exhibiting his sousIlya (accessibility).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faq</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/faq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;frequently-asked-questions&#34;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contents:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#rationale&#34;&gt;THE RATIONALE FOR THIS BLOG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34;&gt;AN OVERVIEW OF INDIAN SYSTEMS OF PHILOSOPHY (DARSHANAS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#vedantathecomplete&#34;&gt;VEDANTA - THE COMPLETE VAIDIKA DARSHANA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#shaivavsvedanta&#34;&gt;THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN SHAIVISM AND VEDANTA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#vishnusupremacy&#34;&gt;PROVING VISHNU’S SUPREMACY FROM THE SHRUTI AND SMRITI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tamilsangam&#34;&gt;THE RELIGIOUS LANDSCAPE OF THE TAMIL SANGAM ERA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#advaitavishnu&#34;&gt;ADVAITA VEDANTA AND ITS ORIGINAL VAISHNAVA CHARACTER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#visishtadvaitadvaita&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION TO VISHISHTADVAITA AND DVAITA (WITH SOME REFERENCES TO OTHER DARSHANAS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-rationale-for-this-blog&#34;&gt;THE RATIONALE FOR THIS BLOG&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What is the purpose of this blog?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ans. To show that Vaishnavism is the true conclusion of vedAnta and that all vedAntins of any persuasion – advaita, vishishtadvaita and dvaita are compulsorily Vaishnavas. Ie, to show that SrimannArAyaNa alone to the exclusion of all other devas is praised as Parabrahman by all shAstra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NArAyaNa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/nArAyaNa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/nArAyaNa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;on-the-name-narayana-used-to-denote-supreme-brahman-in-the-vedas&#34;&gt;On the name &amp;ldquo;Narayana&amp;rdquo; used to denote Supreme Brahman in the Vedas&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an article regarding the word &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;nArAyaNa&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;. It is well known that &lt;em&gt;vaiShNavas&lt;/em&gt; prove &lt;em&gt;viShNu paratva&lt;/em&gt; (Supremacy of Lord Vishnu) using the name &lt;em&gt;nArAyaNa&lt;/em&gt;. One can look into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://narayanastra.blogspot.com/p/blog-page_7196.html&#34;&gt;introduction of the SrI Rudram vyAkhyAna&lt;/a&gt; on this blog to understand how &lt;em&gt;viShNu paratva&lt;/em&gt; is arrived at.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The shaivas pose the following argument:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;nArAyaNa&lt;/em&gt;, even if it means a proper noun according to panini can still denote Shiva as he can be equated to this deity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NArAyaNa sUkta</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/nArAyaNa-sUkta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/nArAyaNa-sUkta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;narayana-suktam----a-srivaishnava-commentary&#34;&gt;Narayana Suktam &amp;ndash; A Srivaishnava commentary&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We believed it is necessary to have a traditional commentary of  this sUkta up on the blog in order to dispel the many erroneous and facetious “interpretations” on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mahAnArAyaNopanishad occurs in the 10th prapataka of the taittiriya araNyaka in the krishNa yajur veda. The Narayana Suktam occuring in this Upanishad needs little introduction as this sUkta is the most important portion of the Veda, next only to the puruSha sUkta. This sUkta identifies the parama-puruSha of the veda as nArAyaNa, which can be understood by the fact that it begins with sahasrasIrsham devam…” just as the puruSha sUkta begins with “sahasrasIrsha purusha:”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On mahAbhArata</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/on_mahAbhArata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/on_mahAbhArata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;understanding-the-mahābhārata&#34;&gt;Understanding the Mahābhārata&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In between publishing the Ishvara Gita, we thought it would be a good idea to write a few articles on the Mahābhāratā. A proper understanding of this ithihāsā will dispel the several illogical and nonsensical ramblings about this work of Shri Vyāsa that is prevalent on the internet thanks to poor interpretations by Sacred-Texts.Com and based on some interpolated sections + misinterpretations propagated by some Veerashaivas and Mahapashupatastra type Neanderthals, who often resort to the Sacred Texts website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAma shvetAshvatara</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/rAma-shvetAshvatara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/rAma-shvetAshvatara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;lord-rama---the-heart-of-rishi-svetasvatara&#34;&gt;Lord Rama - The Heart of Rishi Svetasvatara&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(This article is a response to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://hara-hara-mahadev.blogspot.com/2010/03/lord-rudra-heart-of-rishi-svetasvatara.html&#34;&gt;shaiva article&lt;/a&gt; that claims that the shvetAshvatara upaniShad talks of Shiva&amp;rsquo;s supremacy.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following slOka is famous as far as the description of srimad rAmAyaNa goes,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;veda vedye pare puMsi jaate dasharathaatmaje |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;vedaHprachetasaadaasiid saakShaad raamaayaNaatmanaa ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meaning:  When the Supreme Reality revealed by the veda took birth (avatAra) as the son of daSharatha, the Vedas took birth (avatAra) as the rAmAyaNa from the mouth of vAlmiki.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ShrIdhara svAmI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/shrIdhara-svAmI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/shrIdhara-svAmI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;new-article-sridhara-swamins-position&#34;&gt;New Article: Sridhara Swamin&amp;rsquo;s position&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our latest article discusses the issue of Hari-Hara aikya vAda and shows how Sridhara Swamin has upheld Vishnu&amp;rsquo;s Supremacy without compromising, in his commentaries on both bhAgavata and Vishnu Purana.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we highlight portions from Sridhara Swamin&amp;rsquo;s commentaries that our adversaries are conveniently silent upon. Using this, we show how to consistently interpret the whole of the Advaita gurus&amp;rsquo; works. Also, we have quoted important portions from the Narayaneeyam of Narayana Bhattathiri that our hari-hara aikya vAdin friends cannot deny.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skambha sUkta</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/skambha-sUkta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/skambha-sUkta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;skambha-sukta---a-sri-vaishnava-commentary-part-1&#34;&gt;Skambha Sukta - A Sri Vaishnava Commentary (Part 1)&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The four Vedas were divided by srI veda vyAsa on the following basis –&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Rg Veda describes the auspicious attributes of sriman nArAyaNa and identifies him alone as the Supreme Reality as vouched by the statements like “ekaM sat viprA bahudhA vadanti” and “yo devAnAm nAmadhA eka eva” Several sUktas glorify nArAyaNa by various names like Agni, Indra, Mitra, Varuna, Rudra, Soma, Vayu, etc. Only that god with all auspicious attributes is the Supreme – kasmai devAya haviShA vidhema reinforces it. This Veda represents the “akAra” of OM as it talks about the glories of viShNu (akAro viShNuvAcakaH, akAravAcyo vAsudevaH).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>taDipatri-keshava errs</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/taDipatri-keshava-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/taDipatri-keshava-errors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CRITICISM OF “VISHISHTADVAITA VISLESHANA VIVECHANAM”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the outset, we would like to reteirate our respect for ShrI mAdhvAchArya and the gurus who succeeded him. That can be clearly seen from our Narayanastra blog where we have quoted shrI mAdhva’s bhAshyas on various topics. The relationship between Vishishtadvaitins and Dvaitins is fairly amicable and has been so over the ages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, it cannot also be denied that the two traditions are rival schools of thought and hence, debates have happened. In this respect, one can say Dvaitins took the first step in attempting to refute certain concepts of Vishishtadvaita –Vyasa Tirtha, Jaya Tirtha, Vijayendra Tirtha and Raghavendra Swami were among the dvaita gurus who tried to establish that some of the tenets of Vishishtadvaita were flawed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TAmasa purANa analysis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/tAmasa-purANa-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/tAmasa-purANa-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;tamasatva-of-certain-puranas-texts-with-little-vedantic-authority&#34;&gt;Tamasatva of certain Puranas: Texts with little Vedantic authority&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This page is a contribution of the Srivaishnava sampradAya follower who represented the side of Vaishnavism with me against the author of the mahapashupatastra blog page. My own comments are added in italics like this, preceded by three % signs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a short article regarding the status of the tAmasa purAnAs in vedAntA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As is well known, the 18 purAnAs are classified into three groups – sattva, rajas and tamas. This classification comes from the purAnAs itself and is accepted by all advaitins, vishishtadvaitins and dvaitins. Yet, some people, frustrated at the fact that all the purAnAs classified as sattva praise Vishnu-nArAyaNa only, have attempted to dismiss this classification using much abused arguments like ‘interpolations’ and ‘vaishnava conspiracy’. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VaiShNava shiShTAchAra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/vaiShNava-shiShTAchAra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/vaiShNava-shiShTAchAra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;choose-your-transliteration-scheme-for-the-sanskrit-portions&#34;&gt;Choose your transliteration scheme for the Sanskrit portions:&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Romanized (Latin/English script - Default) script&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Devanagari Lipi&lt;br&gt;&#xA;ITRANS (Search-friendly romanized)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;śiṣṭācāra vivecanam: On the symbols and practices of Vaishnavism (Urdhva Pundra and other topics)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“vidyāvinayasampannā brāhmaṇā vedapāragāḥ ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;mayi bhaktiṃ na kurvanti ye te caṇḍālatāṃ gatāḥ ॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;brāhmaṇo vaiṣṇavo jñeyo na hyasmādanyadevatā ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;mātṛvat parirakṣantaṃ jagatsraṣṭāramīśvaram ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;yo hi nārcayate mūḍhastamāhurbrahmaghātakam ॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;vṛthā japtaṃ vṛthā dattaṃ vṛthā ceṣṭaṃ vṛthā hutam ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;vṛthā tapyaṃ ca taptañca yo na bhakto mayi dvijaḥ ॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;yatkṛtaṃ hutañcāpi yadiṣṭaṃ dattameva vā ।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;avaiṣṇavakṛtaṃ sarvaṃ rākṣasā eva bhuñjate ॥”&lt;br&gt;&#xA;“विद्याविनयसम्पन्ना ब्राह्मणा वेदपारगाः । मयि भक्तिं न कुर्वन्ति ये ते चण्डालतां गताः ॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;ब्राह्मणो वैष्णवो ज्ञेयो न ह्यस्मादन्यदेवता । मातृवत् परिरक्षन्तं जगत्स्रष्टारमीश्वरम् । यो हि नार्चयते मूढस्तमाहुर्ब्रह्मघातकम् ॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;वृथा जप्तं वृथा दत्तं वृथा चेष्टं वृथा हुतम् । वृथा तप्यं च तप्तञ्च यो न भक्तो मयि द्विजः ॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;यत्कृतं हुतञ्चापि यदिष्टं दत्तमेव वा । अवैष्णवकृतं सर्वं राक्षसा एव भुञ्जते ॥”&lt;br&gt;&#xA;“vidyAvinayasampannA brAhmaNA vedapAragAH |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;mayi bhaktiM na kurvanti ye te chaNDAlatAM gatAH ||&lt;br&gt;&#xA;brAhmaNo vaiShNavo j&lt;del&gt;neyo na hyasmAdanyadevatA |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;mAtRRivat parirakShantaM jagatsraShTAramIshvaram |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;yo hi nArchayate mUDhastamAhurbrahmaghAtakam ||&lt;br&gt;&#xA;vRRithA japtaM vRRithA dattaM vRRithA cheShTaM vRRithA hutam |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;vRRithA tapyaM cha tapta&lt;/del&gt;ncha yo na bhakto mayi dvijaH ||&lt;br&gt;&#xA;yatkRRitaM huta&lt;del&gt;nchApi yadiShTaM dattameva vA |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;avaiShNavakRRitaM sarvaM rAkShasA eva bhu&lt;/del&gt;njate ||”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VaiShNavopabRMhaNas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/vaiShNavopabRMhaNas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/lokAchArya-shAkhA/nArAyaNAstra-vRndam/vaiShNavopabRMhaNas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;new-article-published-vaishnava-para-upabrimhana-of-certain-shrutis-in-puranas&#34;&gt;New article published: &amp;ldquo;Vaishnava-para upabrimhana of certain Shrutis in Puranas&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to bring out the next long article we are publishing in our site. If you would like to skip this journal entry and rather read the whole article, &lt;a href=&#34;http://narayanastra.blogspot.com/p/vaishnava-para-upabrimhana-of-certain.html&#34;&gt;here is the link&lt;/a&gt;. For those who need a bit of an overview first, you are currently reading a quick introduction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It covers two topics: “NARADA-BRAHMA SAMVADA IN ANUSHASANIKA PARVAN / NARASIMHA PURANA” and “SHLOKAS ON NARASIMHA IN THE NARADA PURANA”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
