<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०१ काल-क्षेप-परम्परा on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०१ काल-क्षेप-परम्परा on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>०१ SrIman Nathamunigal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/01_SrIman_Nathamunigal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/01_SrIman_Nathamunigal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ज्येष्ठेनूराधा सम्भूतं वीरनारायणे पुरे। गजवक्त्रांशमाचार्यमाद्यं नाथमुनिं भजे॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;jeyeshThe anUrAdhAsambhUtam vIranArAyaNe pure | gajavaktrAmSam AcAryam Adyam nAthamunim bhaje ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the divya deSam of Veeranarayanapuram lived ISvaramunigal, a parama SrIvaishaNava belonging to shaThamarshaNa gotra of coTTai Kulam. He was blessed with a son in Kali yugam 3985, Sobhakrt year, Ani month when AnurAdA nakshtram was ascendance. The child was named as Nathar. Nathar was initiated into the ritualistic formalities such as jAtakarma and Veda VedAnta practice at the appropriate age. SrI Nathar was steeped in devotion and mastered all the Veda SAstras and gained a reputation over his mastery of Veda SAstras and devotion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०२ SrI PuNDarIkAkshar (UyyakkoNDAr)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/02_SrI_PuNDarIkAkshar_UyyakkoNDAr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/02_SrI_PuNDarIkAkshar_UyyakkoNDAr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;चैत्रमासे कृAत्तिकायां श्रीश्वेताद्रिसमुद्भवम् ।&#xA;गुरुंA श्रीपुण्डरीकाक्षं जयत्सेनांशमाश्रये॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;caitramAse krttikAyAm SrISvetAdri samudbhavam | gurum SrIpuNDarIkAksham jayatsenAmSam ASraye ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SrI Pundarrikakshar was born in the divya deSam of Tiruvellarai in the Kali yugam (3987), Prabhava year, Cittirai month, under KrittikA nakshatram as the avatAram of JayatsenAmsar who is one of the chieftains of Vishvaksenar. He was the pradhAna Sishya of SrI Nathamunigal. Further, Kurugai Kaavalappan, Nambikarunakara dAsar, ERu TiruvudaiyAr, TirukannamangaiyANDAn, VaanamAdeviyANDAn, uruppattUr AccAnpiLLai and cOkattUrAzhvAn are also SishyAs of Sri Nathamunigal. SrI Nathamunigal was doing upadeSam to these eight SishyAs on mantra, mantrArthams, divya Prabandham and their viSeshArthams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०३ SrIrAmamiSrar (MaNakkAl Nambi)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/03_SrIrAmamiSrar_MaNakkAl_Nambi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/03_SrIrAmamiSrar_MaNakkAl_Nambi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;माखे मखायां सम्भूतं श्रीरङ्गनगरान्तिके। कुमुदांशं राममिश्रमुपासेऽहं जगद्गAुरुम् ॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;mAkhe makhAyAm sambhUtam SrIranganagarAntike | kumudAmSam rAmamiSram upAse aham jagadgurum ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SrIrAmamiSrar was born in the kali yugam year around 4052, Virodhikrut year, month of mAsi when the star Magham was in ascendance. He was the incarnation of Kumudar (one of the dvArapAlaka-s at SrI VaikuNTham). He was born in the agrahAram known as Manakkal on the banks of Kaveri River, eastern side of Srirangam in Chola deSam. Going by the birth place of him, he was popularly known as Manakkal Nambi. He was the pradAna Sishya of Uyyakkondar and learnt Veda vedantAs thoroughly by serving his AcAryan. When Uyyakkondar&amp;rsquo;s wife attained paramapadam, Manakkal Nambi took charge of the cooking service too for his AcAryan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०४ SrI Alavandar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/04_SrI_Alavandar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/04_SrI_Alavandar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;आषाडेचोत्तराषाडसम्भूतं तत्र वै पुरे। सिंहाननांशं विख्यातं श्रीयामुनमुनिं भजे॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AshADe ca uttarAshADasambhutam tatra vai pure | simhAsananAmSam vikhyAtAm SriyAmunim bhaje ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the banks of Cauvery River, there was an agrhAram known as Veeranarayanapuram. Here, more than a thousand years ago was born SrI Alavandar on dhAtu samvatsaram, ADi month, when Uttirada Naksharam was on the ascent. He is the grandson of SrI Nathamunigal, the first propagator of SrI ViSishTAdvaita siddhAntam. SrI Nathamunigal went once on a pilgrimage to northern region of India with his father, ISvara Bhattar and his son, ISvaramuni. After taking bath in many sacred rivers, and visits to sacred temples, they arrived at the beautiful temple town of BrundAvanam known for the myriad sports of Lord Krishna. They were enchanted by the beauty of BrundAvanam. They decided to extend their stay by a few more days. Thereafter, they took leave of BhagavAn, the BrundAvanacaran and returned to their home in Veeranarayanapuram. While SrI Nathamunigal was staying at BrundAvanam, he became the object of the special anugraham of Lord Krishna, the Yamunaitturaivan on the banks of Yamuna River. SrI Nathamunigal developed extraordinary bhakti now for Kannan, the Yamunaitturaivan. Because of the deep devotion to the Lord Krishna, Nathamunigal wanted to name the child that will be born to his son ISvaramuni as Yamunaitturaivan. Accordingly when the male child was born he was named as Yamunaitturaivan. As this child grew up to become a renowned AcAryan, he acquired the names of SvAmi Alavandar and YaamunAcAriyar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०५ MahApUrNar (Periya Nambigal)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/05_MahApUrNar_Periya_Nambigal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/05_MahApUrNar_Periya_Nambigal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ज्येष्ठायां मार्गशीर्षेतु श्रीरङ्ग क्षेत्रसम्भवम् ।&#xA;महापूर्णं गुरूत्तंशं कुमुदाक्षांशम् आश्रये॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;jyeshThAyAm mArgaSIrshetu SrIranga kshetrasambhavam | mahApUrNam gurUttamSam kumudAkshAmSam ASraye ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During Kali Yugam, in HeviLambi year, mArghazhi month when JyeshTha nakshatram was in ascendance, a child was born as the amSam/incarnation of KumudAkshar at Srirangam in BhAradvAja gotra. He was known as Periya Nambhigal. He was the pradAna Sishya (principal disciple) of SrI Alavandar. As per the command (niyamanam) of his AcAryan, Periya Nambhigal stayed at Srirangam and was conducting upadeSams to his disciples, the traditional granthams of SrI ViSishTAdvaita siddhAntam. His six SishyAs are EmperumAnAr (Ramanuja), Malai kuniya ninRAr, Arya SrISaThakopa dAsar, aNiyarangattamudanAr, tiruvAikkulamudaiyAn Bhattar and Tirukkacchi Nambhigal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०६ EmperumAnAr</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/06_EmperumAnAr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/06_EmperumAnAr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;चैत्राद्रासम्भवं विष्णोः दर्शनस्थापनोत्सुक्तम् ।&#xA;तुण्डीरमण्डले शेषमूर्तिं रामानुजं भजे॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;caitrAdrA sambhavam vishNoH darSanasthApanotsuktam | tuNDIramaNDale SeshamUrtim rAmAnujam bhaje ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SeshAvatAram&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Periya Tirumalai Nambi, one of the SishyAs of SrI Alavandar had two sisters named BhUmi PirATTi and PeriyA PirATTi. The elder one BhUmi PirATTi was given in marriage to AsUrikula tilakar, Kesavaperumal of Sriperumbudur. The younger one, PeriyA PiraTTi was married to Kamalanayana Bhattar of Madhuramangalam village. The sisters were happily living in the villages of their respective in laws. Periya Tirumalai Nambi blessed both of them to beget meritorious boys. He d left for Tirumalai where he was performing kaimkaryam and prayers to Tiruvengadamudaiyan daily. As time went by, over one thousand years ago in the year of Pingala, Cittirai month, Sukla paksha pancami tithi when ArudrA nakshatram was in ascendance, a male child to redeem the world was born to SrI Kesavaperumal. This child was the incarnation of Adi SeshAn as ordained (niyamanam) by SrIman Narayanan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०७ KurukeSar (TirukkurukaippirAn PiLLAn)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/07_KurukeSar_TirukkurukaippirAn_PiLLAn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/07_KurukeSar_TirukkurukaippirAn_PiLLAn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;तुलायां वेङ्कटाद्रौ तु पूर्वाषाढासमुद्भवम् ।&#xA;कुरुकेशं प्रचण्डांसं वन्दे श्रीशैलपूर्णजम् ॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;tulAyAm venkaTAdrau tu pUrvAshADAsamudbhavam | kurukeSam pracaNDAmsam vande SrISailapUrNajam ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;KurukeSar, an amSam (incarnation) of PracANDar was born in Kali Yugam during a SrImukha year, when pUrADa (pUrvAshADhA) nakshatram was in ascendance. He belonged to SaThamarshaNa gotram. He was the second son of Periya Tirumalai Nambhigal, who named his son as &amp;ldquo;PiLLAn&amp;rdquo;. From his childhood days, PiLLAn was listening to his father interpreting the meanings of the pAsurams of TiruvAimozhi and reflected on them even when he was playing. PiLLAn became a disciple of EmperumAnAr and learnt the meanings of all SAstrams form his AcAryan. PiLLAn created a commentary known as &amp;ldquo;TiruvARAyirappaDi&amp;rdquo; following the command of his AcAryan. Udaiyavar named that commentary as &amp;ldquo;Bhagavad Vishayam&amp;rdquo; and ordered that this commentary be included along with the kAlakshepa granthams like Sri BhAshyam. Following his own AcAryan Alavandar&amp;rsquo;s wish and command, EmperumAnAr gave the name of SvAmi NammAzhvAr to PiLLAn. From then on, the name of PiLLAn came to be known as &amp;ldquo;TirukkurukaipirAn PiLLAn&amp;rdquo;. EmperumAnAr made PiLLAn as one of the SrI BhAshya simhAsanAdipatis and commanded PiLLAn to perform kAlakshepams and be his successor after his own ascent to Paramapadam. PiLLAn followed his AcAryan&amp;rsquo;s command and conducted ubhaya VedAnta kAlakshepams at Srirangam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०८ SrI VishNu Cittar (engaLAzhvAn)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/08_SrI_VishNu_Cittar_engaLAzhvAn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/08_SrI_VishNu_Cittar_engaLAzhvAn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;स्वात्यां वैशाखमासे तु श्रीश्वेताद्रिसमुद्भवम् ।&#xA;विजयांशं विष्णुचित्तं गुरुवर्यमहं भजे॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;svAtyAm vaiSAkhamAse tu SrISvetAdrisamudbhavam vijayAmSam vishNucittam guruvaryam aham bhaje ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the divya deSam of Tiruvellarai near Srirangam, during a Keelaka year of Kali Yugam, VaikASi month, engaLAzhvAn incarnated as the amSam of the nityasUri, Vijaya when SvAti nakshatram was in ascendance at the time of his birth. He taught sampradAya granthams through the kAlakshepam route to his SishyAs and stayed at Srirangam. He created a commentary for SrI VishNu PurANam known as &amp;ldquo;Sri VishNu cittIyam&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>०९ VaradadeSikar (NaDAdUr ammal)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/09_VaradadeSikar_NaDAdUr_ammal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/09_VaradadeSikar_NaDAdUr_ammal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;चैत्रे चित्रोद्भवं काञ्च्यां देवराजगुरोः सुतम् ।&#xA;सुभद्रांशं गुरुत्तंशं वरदमाश्रये॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;caitre citrodbhavam kAncyAm devarAjaguroH sutam | subhadrAmSam guruttamSam varadamASraye ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the year 4977, Kali yugam, Paartiva year, month of Chittirai, when ChitrA nakshatram was in ascendance, SrI Varada DeSikar was born as the amSam of Subhadrar in SrIvatsa gotram to Sri Devarajacharyar at Kanchipuram.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The glories of the lineage (Kulam)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SrIman Nathamunigal had two bhAgineyas (marumAns/nephews). They belonged to SrIvatsa gotram. They were known as MelaiyakattAzhvAn and KeezhaiyakattzhvAn. Their names are Varadacharyar and Krishnamachayar respectively. SvAmi DeSikan celebrated them as &amp;ldquo;kALam valampuri ennum naRkkAdalaDiyavar&amp;rdquo;. They debated with majestic voices reminding one of kAhaLa vAdyam and dakshNavartta (Valampuri) Sankham. Their AcAryan, SrIman Nathamunigal was overjoyed with the victorious debates of his nephews. SvAmi DeSikan saluted them as &amp;ldquo;naRkkAdalaDiyavar &amp;quot; since they had remarkable Bhagavad bhakti. SrIman Nathamunigal performed upadeSam on Yoga Saastram. He also taught them Tamil Vedam (divya Prabandham) with rAgam and tALam. Among the two nephews, Varadacharyar created the Yoga grantham of &amp;ldquo;SrIdhara yogAbdi&amp;rdquo;. Krishnamacharyar blessed us with another Yoga grantham named &amp;ldquo;SrIdharakalpataru&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>१० appiLLAr (KiDAmbi Ramanujachariyar)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/10_appiLLAr_KiDAmbi_Ramanujachariyar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/10_appiLLAr_KiDAmbi_Ramanujachariyar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;चैत्रार्द्रासम्भवं काञ्च्यां रङ्गराजगुरोः सुतम् ।&#xA;सुप्रतिष्ठांशमात्रेयं रामानुजगुरुंA भजे॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;caitrArdrAsambhavam kAncyAm rangarAjaguroH sutam | supratishThAmSamAtreyam rAmAnujagurum bhaje ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SrI Rangarajar performed upadeSams on the meanings which he had received from SrI Ramanuja PiLLAn for his SishyAs. During Kali Yugam, Vikrama samvatsaram, Chittirai month, when ArudrA nakshatram was in ascendance, a son was born to SrI Rangarajar. The child was the amSam of a nityasUri, SupratishThar. The child was named with the same name as that of his Guru, Ramanuja PiLLAn. At the appropriate time, the samskArams like upanayanam were carried out. Ramanujar was a genius to acquire all VidyAs from his days as a youth. Elder scholars who saw Ramanujar wondered whether he is appiLLAn (Ramanuja PiLLAn). From then on, he was called appiLLAr.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>११ SrImad VedAntadeSikar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/11_SrImad_VedAntadeSikar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/11_SrImad_VedAntadeSikar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;नभस्यमासि श्रोणायामनन्तार्यगुरूद्भवम् ।&#xA;श्रीवेङ्कटेशघण्टांशं वेदान्तगुरुमाश्रये॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;nabhasyAmi SroNAyAm anantAryagurUdbhavam | SrIvenkaTeSaghaNTAmSam vedAntagurumASraye ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Among the seven mukti kshetrams, the most important one is at Kanchipuram and near it, is the divya deSam of Tiruttanka. The sannidhi of Lord dIpaprakASar is here. Near by is the agrahAram of tUppul. It means sacred grass - viSvAmitram (darbham). Learned people state that tUppul agrahAram is named that way because of many scholars born in the ViSvAmitra gotram were living there. There lived one by the name, Ananta SomayAji who was performing yaj~nAs. His son was PuNDarIkAksha dIkshitar whose son was AnantasUri. ApiLLAr gave away his younger sister, totArambA, daughter of SrIrangarajacharyar in marriage to AnantasUri. This dampati&amp;rsquo;s life went on smoothly observing bhagavad bhAgavata ArAdhanam and the daily rites done during the five divisions of the day (pancakAla parAyaNar).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>१२ SrI Kumara Varadacharyar &amp; SrI BrahmatantrasvatAntra SvAmi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/12_SrI_Kumara_Varadacharyar_SrI_Brahmata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/12_SrI_Kumara_Varadacharyar_SrI_Brahmata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;श्रावणे मासि रोहिण्यां जातं वेङ्कटदेशिकात् ।&#xA;विश्वामित्रान्वयाब्धीन्दुं वरदार्यमहं भजे॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SrAvaNe mAsi rohiNyAm jAtam venkaTadeSikAt | viSvAmitrAnvayAbdhIndum varadAryamaham bhaje ||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SvAmi DeSikan&amp;rsquo;s tirukkumArar SrI Kumara Varadacharyar popularly knowa as SrI NayinArAchAryar was born with the divine blessings of DevAdirAja Perumal of Kanchipuram. As said by the vAkyams &amp;ldquo;pituHSatAguNam putraH&amp;rdquo;, he had all the guNams like his father, SvAmi DeSikan. He was a scholar of par excellence. He was giving discourses on the sampradAya granthams at Srirangam along with SrI Brahmatantrasvatantra SvAmi. After his father attained Paramapadam, he stayed in Srirangam for a year. He concluded all the year long rituals for his revered father. Then he started on sancAram along with Brahmatantrasvatantra SvAmi to perform MangaLASAsanam of several divya deSa EmperumAns and to win over the debates with scholars of other religious belief and establish ViSishTAdvaita sampradAyam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>१३ GaTikASaTam ammal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/13_GaTikASaTam_ammal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/ahobila-shAkhA/AchArya-vaibhava_en/01_kAlaxepa-paramparA/13_GaTikASaTam_ammal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This MahAn was the pradAna Sishya of Brahma tantrasvatantra SvAmi. He was born at Perumal Koyil in the month of Chittirai when Hasta nakshatram was in ascendance. He was born to SrI Devaraja Perumal of SrIvatsa Gotram and hailed from the vamSam of NadAdur Ammal. Since his avatAram took place on the avatAra day of PerAruLALan, he was named as Varadan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He was doing discourse on VaishNava siddhAntam at Kanchipuram. He has authored granthams like YatirAja Vijayam and others. His pradAna Sishya was SrImad Adi vaN SaThakopa YatIndra mahAdeSikan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
