<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;ranga-varadau on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/en/ranga-varadau/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;ranga-varadau on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/en/ranga-varadau/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/en/ranga-varadau/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/en/ranga-varadau/1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SRI-BHASHYA.&#xA;157-241&#xA;The Brahmavädin Series.&#xA;THE SRI-BHÂSHYA.PUBLISHED BY&#xA;M. C. ALASINGAPPERUMAL, B. A..&#xA;The &amp;ldquo;Brahmavadin&amp;rdquo; Press,&#xA;TRIPLICANE, MADRAS.&#xA;THE&#xA;VEDANTA-SUTRAS&#xA;WITH THE&#xA;SRI-BHASHYA&#xA;OF&#xA;RAMANUJACHARYA.&#xA;Translated into English&#xA;BY&#xA;M. RANGACHARYA, M.A.,&#xA;AND&#xA;M. B. VARADARĀJA AIYANGAR, B.A., B.L.&#xA;VOLUME I.&#xA;adras:&#xA;THE &amp;ldquo;BRAHMAVADIN&amp;rdquo; PRESS.&#xA;1899.&#xA;(All Rights Reserved.)&#xA;THIS VOLUME&#xA;IS DEDICATED TO&#xA;The Right Honourable Professor F. Max Muller,&#xA;by the&#xA;TRANSLATORS&#xA;in grateful recognition of his valuable services rendered&#xA;to the cause of Sanskrit Literature.&#xA;取卵&#xA;2052105PREFACE.&#xA;HIS is the first of the three volumes in which it is pro-&#xA;THIS&#xA;posed to bring out an English translation of Ràmâ. nujacharya&amp;rsquo;s Sri-Bhashya, his well-known commentary on the Vedanta-Sutras of Badarayana. The Vedanta of India has now fully established its title to occupy a prominent place among the various systems of philosophy known to the world; and one aspect of it commonly called the Adwaita- Vedanta has long been familiar to European scholars, and has even met with fair recognition at their hands. Rāmā- nujacharya&amp;rsquo;s Sri Bhashya, is an exposition of the Visishta- dwaita aspect thereof, and it well deserves to be quite as widely known and appreciated as the Adwaita-Vedanta of Sankaracharya. The Visishtadwaitins represent a school of Vedantic thought, of which Sankaracharya himself has taken cognisance in his writings, and there is evidence to shew that it must have come down in the form of an un- broken tradition from very ancient times. The Bhagava- tas and Pancharatras, who have obviously played a very im- portant part in the history of Hindu religion, are in all probability the original system-makers of this school, which appears to be as old as the Upanishads themselves. The Upanishads and the Bagavadgita teach both jñana and bhaktı; that is, they teach that both wisdom and worship are capable of forming the means for the attain- ment of salvation. All along in &amp;lsquo;our history some seekers after truth and salvation may be seen to have relied more upon wisdom than upon worship, while others have relied&#xA;ii&#xA;more upon worship than upon wisdom. This division in religious thought is truly representative of two dissimilar innate tendencies in human nature, and the Bhāgavatas belong to the latter class. How far the Visishtãdwarta school interprets the Upanishads and the Bagavadgita aright is thus a question to which each earnest student of the Vedanta has to find his own answer. The discussion of the various Vedantic problems dealt with in this volume is so full and so well expressive of the fundamental con- clusions embodied in the Sri-Bhashya that it gives the volume a characteristic completeness, in spite of its being only a part of the whole work. It is therefore expected that students of Indian philosophy and Hindu religion will find this volume to be interesting and instructive.&#xA;For the purposes of this translation we have consulted three editions of the Sri-Bhashya-the Madras edition printed in Telugu characters, the Benares edition in Deva- nagari characters, and the incomplete Calcutta edition, also in Devanagari characters and published by the Asiatic Society, We have found the Madras edition the most accurate among these, and have accordingly followed it in our trans- lation. The style of the Sri-Bhashya is severely argumen- tative and controversial, and it is also technical and terse. We have, however, tried our best to make the translation smooth and intelligible without any way sacrificing its faithfulness to the original. The additions and alterations needed to make the English rendering full and accurate are all enclosed within curved brackets; and the references to the various quotations and authorities cited in the work are generally given within square brackets, a few of these references being also given in foot-notes. Foot-notes have beer sparingly given, and only in places where it was thought they were absolutely necessary for the elucidation.&#xA;and proper understanding of the text of the translation. With the object of enabling the readers to make out easily the nature and the relations between the vari- ous parts of the closely reasoned arguments to be found in this volume, we have given in the beginning an analytical outline of the contents of the volume. A table showing our system of transliteration and a list containing the abbreviations used by us are given at the end of the volume. The word atman is used in Sans- krit to denote the Brahman as well as the jiva; hence it has been translated as Self where it denotes the former and as self where it denotes the latter; and the pronouns who and which have been more or less indiscriminately used in relation to both of them. The word karman has been uniformly used in the form of karma, and its plural is given as karmas, as these forms seem to have be- come fairly current in English. The printing work has had to be done somewhat hurriedly, and a few errors have unavoidably crept in. The more serious ones among them are pointed out and corrected in a list of errata appended hereto. We do not know how far our English rendering of the Sri-Bhashya is all that it should be, but we have spared no pains to make it as good as we can.&#xA;We are well aware that it is capable of much improvement; and yet it may not perhaps be too much to hope that our attempt to present faithfully in English the thoughts of one of India&amp;rsquo;s great teachers and religious reformers will be productive of sonie good in the way of helping on the world&amp;rsquo;s appreciation of India&amp;rsquo;s philosophic integrity and religious earnestness.&#xA;NOVEMBER, 1899.&#xA;MADRAS.&#xA;M. R.&#xA;M. V. B.CONTENTS.&#xA;CHAPTER I.&#xA;PART I.&#xA;PAGE.&#xA;i-lxxv.&#xA;:::&#xA;I.&#xA;257- 264.&#xA;&amp;hellip;&#xA;284.&#xA;328.&#xA;..&#xA;346.&#xA;400.&#xA;409.&#xA;&amp;hellip;&#xA;417.&#xA;419.&#xA;425.&#xA;437.&#xA;439.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/en/ranga-varadau/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/en/ranga-varadau/2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE&#xA;VEDANTA-SŪTRAS&#xA;WITH THE&#xA;SRI-BHASHYA&#xA;OF&#xA;RĀMĀNUJĀCHĀRYA&#xA;Translated into English&#xA;BY&#xA;M. RANGACHARYA, M.A.&#xA;AND&#xA;M. B. VARADARAJA AIYANGAR, B.A., B.L.&#xA;VOLUME II.&#xA;(Pushed with the financial assistance of the Ministry of Education,&#xA;the Government of India.)&#xA;THE EDUCATIONAL PUBLISHING CO.,&#xA;NUNGAMBAKKAM ::&#xA;MADRAS-6.&#xA;All Rights Reserved.]&#xA;1964&#xA;[Price Rs. 12:50 nP.&#xA;First Edition-April 1964.&#xA;VIDYA PRESS, 16, SUNKUWAR STREET, MADRAS-5.&#xA;PREFACE&#xA;It has taken more time than we expected to bring out the second volume of this work. Every care has been taken to see that the translation is accurate and clear. The additions and alterations necessary to make the translation full and complete are enclosed within brackets.&#xA;The Analytical Outline is for the most part our work. Many footnotes have also been added by us. The footnotes are based largely on the indispensable Srutaprakāsika, the Bhavaprakāšikā and the lucid commentaries of Rangarāmānuja on the Upanishads. The indexes have also been prepared by us.&#xA;We are grateful to the Government of India for sanctioning a grant to help in the publication of this work. To the late Sri M. Patanjali Sastri and other members of the Sanskrit Board who must have recommended the grant, our thanks are due, and are gladly rendered.&#xA;In the elucidation of the difficult technical arguments in this work, we have received invaluable help from Sanskrit scholars. Particular mention has to be made of Sri Karappangadu Venkaṭācharya Swami, who has spared many hours to explain Ramanuja&amp;rsquo;s ideas and clear patiently doubts and difficulties.&#xA;We have to acknowledge thankfully the help given by Sri T. E. Varadachariar, Sri M. C. Krishnan and&#xA;and Sri T. E. Seshadri in seeing the book through the press. The printing of Volume III has already started.&#xA;April 1964.&#xA;M. R. SAMPATKUMARAN,&#xA;M. B. NARASIMHA IYENGAR.&#xA;CONTENTS&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/en/ranga-varadau/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/rAmAnujaH/shrI-bhAShyam/en/ranga-varadau/3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE&#xA;VEDANTA-SŪTRAS&#xA;WITH THE&#xA;ŚRI-BHASHYA&#xA;OF&#xA;RAMANUJACHARYA&#xA;Translated into English&#xA;BY&#xA;M. RANGACHARYA, MA.&#xA;AND&#xA;M. B. VARADARAJA AIYANGAR, B.A., B.L.&#xA;VOLUME III.&#xA;(Published with the financial assistance of the Ministry of Education, the Government of India.)&#xA;THE EDUCATIONAL PUBLISHING CO.,&#xA;NUNGAMBAKKAM ::&#xA;MADRAS-6.&#xA;All Rights Reserved.] 1965&#xA;[Price Rs. 15.&#xA;First Edition-December 1965,&#xA;VIDYA PRESS, 16, SUNKUWAR STREET, MADRAS-5.&#xA;PREFACE&#xA;·&#xA;The progress of the printing of this third volume was satisfactory till a serious breakdown in the health of one of us. However, after an interruption of some months, work was resumed and thankfully completed.&#xA;The Analytical Outline, most of the footnotes and the indexes have been prepared by us. In view of the bulk of this volume, it has not been found feasible to include in it, as originally hoped, a brief study of Rāmānuja&amp;rsquo;s philosophy and criticisms&#xA;thereon.&#xA;Our thanks are again due to Sri Karappaṁgādu Venkatacharya Svāmin for his patient and illuminating explanations of the many difficulties and complexities encountered. Sri R. C. Srinivasa- raghavan helped in preparing the indexes and Sri M. C. Krishnan in seeing the book through the press. We thank them for their services.&#xA;M. R. SAMPATKUMARAN,&#xA;December, 1965.&#xA;M. B. NARASIMHA IYENGAR.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
