<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/rAmAnanda-shAkhA/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/rAmAnanda-shAkhA/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BhagavadAchArya split</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/rAmAnanda-shAkhA/articles/bhagavadAchArya-split/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/rAmAnanda-shAkhA/articles/bhagavadAchArya-split/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What it is interesting to notice, comparing the information given by Sinha and Saraswati, is that the number of schools supported by Rāmānandīs has increased. Sinha and Saraswati claim that of 41 centres, there were only &amp;rsquo;three Sanskrit pāṭhśālās [Sanskit schools for children] run by Rāmānandis and they are besides not very active&amp;rsquo; (1978: 130). Among the 21 places I visited, however, nine had Sanskrit schools, and brahmacārīs were indeed their main occupants.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Darknight on bhagavadAchArya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/rAmAnanda-shAkhA/articles/darknight_on_bhagavadAchArya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/rAmAnanda-shAkhA/articles/darknight_on_bhagavadAchArya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The actual issue with few rAmAnandis like bhagavadAcharya was about the presence of sri rAmAnuja in the guru parampara.&#xA;They did not want the lineage to continue from rAmAnujAcharya, they wanted to separate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He made afalse claim that sri rAmAnuja was never part of guru parampara which is totally false because their own grantha bhakti mAla says the sampradaya emerged from rAmAnuja sampardAya. This was noted by PBA swami in 1940 itself he said rAmAnandis initially accepted that they were from lineage of uch as Namalvar, Nath Muni, Udayavar, and Manavala Mamunigal , but some group was not broke and they themselves called upon as direct lineage of rAmAnandi not sri vaishnava.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>आनन्दभाष्यसिंहासनासीनजी</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/rAmAnanda-shAkhA/articles/Ananda-bhAShya-siMhAsanAdhipaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/paramparA/rAmAnanda-shAkhA/articles/Ananda-bhAShya-siMhAsanAdhipaH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(श्री-वैष्णव-मताब्ज-भास्कर-प्रस्तावात्)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;सम्प्रदाय&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;प्रस्तोता—आनन्दभाष्यसिंहासनासीनजी&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;सम्, प्र उपसर्ग पूर्वक दा धातु से निष्पन्न यह सम्प्रदाय शब्द है। ‘अथाम्नायः सम्प्रदायः’ इस कोष वचन के अनुसार गुरु-परम्परागत प्राप्त होने वाले या प्रचलित उपदेश को सम्प्रदाय कहते हैं, जो अनादिकाल से चलता आया हुआ है, एवं जिसका वर्णन वेद, उपनिषद्, संहिता आदि शास्त्रों में उपलब्ध होता है। श्रीरामानन्द-सम्प्रदाय का वर्णन ऋग्वेद के दशवें मण्डल ११७ सूक्त ७वें मन्त्र में उपलब्ध होता है, एवं अथर्ववेदीय श्रीरामतापनीयोपनिषद् के उत्तरभाग के चौथे पैराग्राफ में श्रीराम-महामन्त्र-जप, अनुष्ठान एवं परम्परा सम्बन्धी उल्लेख प्राप्त होता है। अथर्ववेदीय श्रीमैथिली-महोपनिषद् के पाँचवें प्रसङ्ग में श्रीसम्प्रदाय यानी श्रीरामानन्द-सम्प्रदाय की आनुपूर्विकी परम्परा उपलब्ध होती है।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
