<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;shrInivAsaH on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/shrInivAsa-siddhAnta-chintAmaNiH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;shrInivAsaH on रामानुजीये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/shrInivAsa-siddhAnta-chintAmaNiH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AmuktamAlyadA thesis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/shrInivAsa-siddhAnta-chintAmaNiH/AmuktamAlyadA_thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/shrInivAsa-siddhAnta-chintAmaNiH/AmuktamAlyadA_thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://shodhganga.inflibnet.ac.in/bitstream/10603/79440/3/amukta_chapter3.pdf&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-the-siddhāntacintāmaṇi---a-detailed-study&#34;&gt;3 THE SIDDHĀNTACINTĀMAṆI - A DETAILED STUDY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Siddāntacintāmaṇi&lt;/em&gt; of Śrīnivāsa II which we have taken up for a detailed study is mainly concerned with establishing the point that Lord Viṣṇu forms both the material and instrumental causes of the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the opening verse the author pays obeisance to the Supreme Brahman Who is &lt;em&gt;advitīya&lt;/em&gt; (Who does not have a second entity as equal to Him) and Who has both Cit and Acit as His body. In the next verse he pays homage to Yatipati (King of Ascetics) i.e., Rāmānuja and Vedānta Deśika, his own grandfather Aṇṇaguru (Aṇṇaya Dīkṣita-I as mentioned in the genealogical table in chapter I), his father (Śrīnivāsa Tātārya I) and his &lt;em&gt;bhāṣyaguru&lt;/em&gt;, Kamalānilaya Makhīśvara (i.e., Śrīnivāsa Dīkṣita). He states that he could have easy access to all the &lt;em&gt;śāstras&lt;/em&gt; due to the grace of his elder brother (Aṇṇaya II) and then undertakes to bring out the secret of the Vedāntas. In another verse he points out that this work is meant for those who, though they have learnt the [[P89]] &lt;em&gt;Siddhānta&lt;/em&gt; (of Viśiṣṭādvaita) in a general way, are not well-versed in the actual doctrines and concepts of the system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
